<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/tags/web/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-11-29 16:15:45 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>IE Exploit Moves from DoS to Remote Code Execution</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/ie-exploit-moves-from-dos-to-remote-code-execution/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 16:15:45 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/ie-exploit-moves-from-dos-to-remote-code-execution/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow-up to my posting &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/11/21/zero-day-ie-exploit/&#34;&gt;Zero-Day IE Exploit&lt;/a&gt;, it has now been discovered that this exploit is no longer just a denial of service (DoS) flaw, but rather a flaw that can allow remote code execution (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.security.ithub.com/article/Unpatched+IE+Flaw+Is+Worse+Than+Expected/166164_1.aspx&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for more information). As of this writing, there is no patch for this vulnerability and the only workaround is to disable Active Scripting in IE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For your convenience, here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.microsoft.com/kb/q154036/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to a Microsoft KB article that describes how to disable Active Scripting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternately, you can just switch to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; (which, by the way, is supposed to release Firefox 1.5 sometime today).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Zero-Day IE Exploit</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/21/zero-day-ie-exploit/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2005 23:02:43 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/21/zero-day-ie-exploit/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1891749,00.asp&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; discusses a newly-discovered zero-day exploit for Internet Explorer, including IE on fully-patched Windows XP SP2 systems. (Apparently, only Windows Server 2003 with the Enhanced Security Configuration is immune.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No patch has been released, and no security advisory had been posted at the time this was written. A Microsoft security advisory was expected at any moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, switch to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt;. No, really&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;m serious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; Microsoft has posted a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/technet/security/advisory/911302.mspx&#34;&gt;security advisory&lt;/a&gt; about this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>It Was Bound to Happen</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/09/it-was-bound-to-happen/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2005 16:17:25 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/09/it-was-bound-to-happen/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;To a certain extent, I agree with the belief that operating systems and applications that don&amp;rsquo;t have a significant market share like Windows, IIS, and Exchange won&amp;rsquo;t get targeted as frequently and therefore will have a &amp;ldquo;better&amp;rdquo; security track record. I don&amp;rsquo;t agree that this is the &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; reason that Linux, Mac OS X, and others haven&amp;rsquo;t seen as many security vulnerabilities and the oh-so-fun network worms that invariably accompany them. But I will agree that as these alternatives gain in popularity, more hackers are going to target them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result, it&amp;rsquo;s no surprise that a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1882889,00.asp&#34;&gt;new Linux worm&lt;/a&gt; has recently emerged. I mean, it was bound to happen. Linux is surging in popularity, as Linus Torvalds and other developers continue to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1881470,00.asp&#34;&gt;add features&lt;/a&gt; to the Linux kernel and more and more corporations deploy Linux. Of course the malware authors are going to try something like this. I doesn&amp;rsquo;t surprise me in the least. While this one is fairly low-tech, you can bet that future variants of this worm (as well as new worms) will be more complex and more dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also fully expect that the anti-Linux crowd will shout that this is the end of the line for Linux, just like the anti-Microsoft crowd shouts &amp;ldquo;Down with Windows!&amp;rdquo; everytime Microsoft patches a critical security flaw that could be exploited by an automated worm (side note: new Microsoft critical security flaw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/technet/security/Bulletin/MS05-053.mspx&#34;&gt;patched yesterday&lt;/a&gt;, go have a look and make sure you are protected). This just isn&amp;rsquo;t the case. Neither Windows nor Linux are going to go away, and each of them has value for businesses today. The best bet for any organization is to use the product that best fits the need and then make sure that the product is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;properly &lt;em&gt;configured&lt;/em&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;properly &lt;em&gt;patched&lt;/em&gt;; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;properly &lt;em&gt;maintained&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following these guidelines, businesses and consumers can safely deploy the products, technologies, and platforms that best meet their needs without falling prey to technology bigotry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Modifying Camino&#39;s Exceptions List for Cookies</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/13/modifying-caminos-exceptions-list-for-cookies/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2005 22:36:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/13/modifying-caminos-exceptions-list-for-cookies/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a stickler about cookies. No, not the kind you eat&amp;hellip;the kind that web servers place on your computer when you visit a web site. I understand that cookies are sometimes necessary to maintain state as a user navigates through a web site; HTTP is, after all, a stateless protocol. But a cookie for every site no matter what? That just gets on my nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until now, I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org/&#34;&gt;Camino&lt;/a&gt; configured to ask if I wanted to allow a cookie or not. This got time-consuming when I was visiting a site I had never visited before and all the ad servers wanted to place a cookie to track me. I wanted a way to tell Camino, &amp;ldquo;Block all cookies unless I say otherwise.&amp;rdquo; Finally, in Camino 0.9a1, I can set all cookies to be denied and then view the exception list, but there was still no way to edit the exception list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being the determined (read: stubborn) person that I am, I was determined to find a way to edit this exceptions list. (As a side note to the Camino developers, please write a UI for editing the exception list.) After not too much searching, I found that the &lt;code&gt;hostperm.1&lt;/code&gt; file in &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Camino&lt;/code&gt; is an ordinary text file that contains the exceptions list. To add a site to this list, simply follow the same format as one of the existing lines, specifying 1 to allow cookies or 2 to deny cookies. Of course, any editing to this file should be done while Camino is not running.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Firefox Updates and Roadmap</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/13/firefox-updates-and-roadmap/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2005 15:51:12 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/13/firefox-updates-and-roadmap/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Mozilla released &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; 1.0.5, which patches a number of security vulnerabilities. You can get more information on the release &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1836310,00.asp&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or by visiting the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org&#34;&gt;Mozilla.org&lt;/a&gt; web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1895,1821168,00.asp&#34;&gt;more information&lt;/a&gt; has been revealed about Firefox 1.1, the next version of the open source web browser. An alpha version of Firefox 1.1 could be ready within just a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Mozilla can continue to innovate with Firefox and address my two primary concerns&amp;ndash;ease of deployment and distributing security updates&amp;ndash;then they will continue to steal market share away from Internet Explorer. If nothing else, Mozilla will at least force Microsoft to be competitive again, and that is a success in and of itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mozilla is also updating &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/products/thunderbird&#34;&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/a&gt;, the companion e-mail client to Firefox, and that update is expected to be available soon as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Camino&#39;s Latest Iteration</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/11/caminos-latest-iteration/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2005 23:24:29 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/11/caminos-latest-iteration/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org&#34;&gt;Camino 0.9a1&lt;/a&gt;, the latest version of the native &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; browser, for the last few days. I have to say that I am impressed. I like the new features on the Go menu that shows the most recently visited websites; this makes it easier to flip back to a site than having to switch to the &amp;ldquo;Bookmarks&amp;rdquo; view. The new tab bar is much better as well; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stand the old one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nada.de/mac/camitools/&#34;&gt;CamiTools&lt;/a&gt; add-ons for Camino 0.9a1 are also excellent; I&amp;rsquo;m using both CamiOptions as well as CamiFlash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using Camino now, you should give this new version a spin. You&amp;rsquo;ll be glad you did.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>YAMB (Yet Another Mac Browser)</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/05/yamb-yet-another-mac-browser/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2005 16:33:03 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/05/yamb-yet-another-mac-browser/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the title may indicate otherwise, I&amp;rsquo;m actually glad to see more browsers popping up for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;. Choice is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new kid on the block this time is &lt;a href=&#34;http://hmdt-web.net/shiira/index-e.html&#34;&gt;Shiira&lt;/a&gt;, a WebKit-based browser that offers some pretty useful features. These features include Tab Expose, which is Expose for browser tabs (activated via F8); &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growl.info/&#34;&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; integration; integration with Safari Bookmarks; and a clean, native Aqua interface. Because it uses Apple&amp;rsquo;s WebKit (now open sourced and available &lt;a href=&#34;http://webkit.opendarwin.org/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), it renders pages the same way as Safari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like some features about Shiira (especially the Growl integration and the tabbed browsing implementation), but still find myself going back to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org/&#34;&gt;Camino&lt;/a&gt;. A new alpha version of Camino 0.9 has been released, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t brought myself to use it yet. If Camino had a way to provide notifications via Growl (I&amp;rsquo;d really like for my browser to notify me when a download is complete), I would be just absolutely thrilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Shiira is an open source project, released under a BSD style license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>A Shameless Plug</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/20/a-shameless-plug/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 21:58:45 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/20/a-shameless-plug/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;OK, I know this is a shameless plug, but I just published an updated version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mercurionsystems.com&#34;&gt;Mercurion Systems web site&lt;/a&gt; this evening. Have a look!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>New del.icio.us Links</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/14/new-delicious-links/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 00:42:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/14/new-delicious-links/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve added a couple new links to &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/slowe/&#34;&gt;my del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; bookmarks. Most notably, I&amp;rsquo;ve added an entry for a recent article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onlamp.com/&#34;&gt;ONLamp.com&lt;/a&gt;, a site hosted by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreillynet.com/&#34;&gt;O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Network&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.modsecurity.org/&#34;&gt;mod_security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onlamp.com/pub/a/onlamp/2005/06/09/wss_security.html?page=1&#34;&gt;Securing Web Services with mod_security&lt;/a&gt;, is a great introduction to an &lt;a href=&#34;http://httpd.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache&lt;/a&gt; module that I&amp;rsquo;ve known about and used for a while now. Similar to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/technet/security/tools/urlscan.mspx&#34;&gt;URLScan&lt;/a&gt; for IIS 5.0, mod_security serves to block malicious URLs and invalid requests, even within encrypted HTTPS sessions. As such, it acts as the perfect complement to firewalls and intrusion detection/prevention systems (both network-based and host-based), which typically operate at lower layers of the networking stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use Apache, I urge you to evaluate and deploy mod_security to enhance your web server&amp;rsquo;s security.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>New Hyperlinking Convention</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/new-hyperlinking-convention/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 14:57:10 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/new-hyperlinking-convention/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m adopting a new hyperlinking convention with this post and all future posts. From this post on (I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been doing this already for the last few posts), I&amp;rsquo;ll only hyperlink the first instance of a company, product, term, etc., rather than all instances of that item within a posting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Switched to a New del.icio.us Account</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/25/switched-to-a-new-delicious-account/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2005 15:13:17 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/25/switched-to-a-new-delicious-account/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the process of trying to clean up all the various accounts and subscriptions and what not that I have out there, I have switched to a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/&#34;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; account. You can now find my bookmark list at &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/slowe/&#34;&gt;del.icio.us/slowe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does anyone know how to close an old del.icio.us account?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Miscellaneous Projects</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/13/miscellaneous-projects/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 22:22:53 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/13/miscellaneous-projects/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In my copious spare time (fellow parents out there know this is a joke), I&amp;rsquo;m working on a couple of miscellaneous technical projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internal news server:&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m having so many problems with NNTP-based access from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.panic.com/unison/&#34;&gt;Unison&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/&#34;&gt;Exchange Server 2003&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to setup an internal NNTP server using Linux and INNd. Linux I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with; INNd is completely new to me. Wish me luck.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IMAP proxy:&lt;/em&gt; This would use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vergenet.net/linux/perdition/&#34;&gt;Perdition&lt;/a&gt; to proxy IMAP4S requests to my mail server. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have Perdition handle IMAP4S and then pass IMAP to the back-end server, offloading the SSL work to the proxy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Squid log analysis:&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a way to parse down the logs from my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org/&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; web cache. Once I find a way to do this, then I can really begin offering Squid and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squidguard.org/&#34;&gt;SquidGuard&lt;/a&gt; as a content filtering solution to some of my customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure this stuff is probably old hat to some of you out there. Feel free to contribute some helpful information or URLs. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you posted on how things proceed with these and other projects as they develop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
