<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/tags/standards/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-11-29 16:45:01 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Open Enough for Massachusetts</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/open-enough-for-massachusetts/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 16:45:01 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/open-enough-for-massachusetts/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Not suprisingly, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s moves to &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; up its XML-based file formats for current and future versions of Microsoft Office have swayed the State of Massachusetts back to its side again. Get the details &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windowsitpro.com/windowspaulthurrott/Article/ArticleID/48590/windowspaulthurrott_48590.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Microsoft Promises Not to Sue</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/microsoft-promises-not-to-sue/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 16:24:54 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/microsoft-promises-not-to-sue/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; recently made a move to &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; up its XML-based file formats for Microsoft Office 2003 and the forthcoming Office 12. These file formats were offered to ECMA International for consideration as a formal open standard. However, the &amp;ldquo;license&amp;rdquo; for these file formats was merely a promise not to sue people violating its patents on the use of the file formats. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1894039,00.asp&#34;&gt;Read more here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1895,1892757,00.asp&#34;&gt;these comments&lt;/a&gt; from a legal analyst regarding Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/office/xml/covenant.mspx&#34;&gt;Patent Protection Covenant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, a promise &amp;ldquo;not to sue&amp;rdquo; from any large corporation&amp;ndash;not just Microsoft&amp;ndash;wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be good enough for me were I a developer. Somehow, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that many developers are going to feel completely comfortable incorporating Office &lt;sup&gt;2003&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; XML-based file formats into their applications based solely on the Patent Protection Covenant. What happens when (not if) the covenant changes?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Microsoft&#39;s Counter-Move</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/21/microsofts-counter-move/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2005 23:16:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/21/microsofts-counter-move/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The rallying cry around OpenDocument prompted Microsoft to make its counter-move. As fully expected, Microsoft is trying to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1891829,00.asp&#34;&gt;create a standard&lt;/a&gt; based on Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s own (until now) proprietary XML formats. Please tell me you saw this coming, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With companies from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.novell.com/&#34;&gt;Novell&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.corel.com/&#34;&gt;Corel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1895,1877815,00.asp&#34;&gt;standing in support&lt;/a&gt; of the OpenDocument format, a new coalition forming in support of the format, and governments agencies such as the State of Massachusetts requiring the use of file formats such as PDF and OpenDocument, clearly Microsoft was worried. Otherwise, why try to create an alternate standard of your own creation? Why not just join the existing standards? Many are also saying that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s decision to include PDF support in the next version of Office is another attempt to keep from being shut out. After all, Office is a major cash cow for Microsoft, so the company will do whatever it can to provent a loss of marketshare (and revenue as a result).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>LSB Recognized by ISO</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/01/lsb-recognized-by-iso/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2005 19:12:19 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/01/lsb-recognized-by-iso/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1880214,00.asp&#34;&gt;News surfaced today&lt;/a&gt; that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iso.org/iso/en/ISOOnline.frontpage&#34;&gt;International Organization for Standardization&lt;/a&gt; (ISO) has approved the Linux Standards Base (LSB) as an international standard. The LSB 2.0.1 core specification has been accepted by the ISO and will be published as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iso.org/iso/en/CatalogueDetailPage.CatalogueDetail?CSNUMBER=41481&amp;amp;scopelist=PROGRAMME&#34;&gt;International Standard 23360&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my eyes, this is a big indicator of Linux&amp;rsquo;s maturity. Does Linux still need growth in some areas to be more competitive with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Windows&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.novell.com/netware/&#34;&gt;Novell NetWare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sun.com/software/solaris/&#34;&gt;Solaris&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;? Yes, certainly. And yet, at the same time, Linux has strengths all its own as well. This recognition by the ISO of the Linux Standards Base serves to further legitimize Linux as a viable and worthy competitor to the proprietary operating systems listed above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(By the way, you&amp;rsquo;ll note that I did not include Novell&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.novell.com/products/openenterpriseserver/&#34;&gt;Open Enterprise Server&lt;/a&gt; in the list of operating systems above because it is, of course, based on Linux.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Nonstandard Implementations</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/14/nonstandard-implementations/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2005 22:24:04 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/14/nonstandard-implementations/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In my experiments with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vergenet.net/linux/perdition/&#34;&gt;Perdition&lt;/a&gt;, I learned a couple of very interesting facts. First, the IMAP4 implementation on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/&#34;&gt;Exchange Server 2003&lt;/a&gt; does not support the STARTTLS command, as described in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.networksorcery.com/enp/rfc/rfc2595.txt&#34;&gt;RFC 2595&lt;/a&gt; and re-affirmed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.networksorcery.com/enp/rfc/rfc3501.txt&#34;&gt;RFC 3501&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, Exchange expects an SSL session to be established immediately, and then IMAP is spoken. This is similar to the &amp;ldquo;smtpd_tls_wrappermode&amp;rdquo; directive that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postfix.org/&#34;&gt;Postfix&lt;/a&gt; supports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, it appears that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; Mail application (commonly referred to as Mail.app) also uses this IMAP-over-SSL approach, since I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Mail.app to connect to Exchange using IMAP with SSL for quite some time. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to confirm that now, but having precious little luck finding any definitive information one way or the other. If anyone knows for certain, please let me know. I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep searching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those things that just makes me crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
