<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/categories/collaboration/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-11-19 23:30:46 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Just About Ready</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/19/just-about-ready/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 19 Nov 2005 23:30:46 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/19/just-about-ready/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This new blog is just about ready for public consumption. I just finished configuring the permalink structure so that all posts have a static URL, using a pretty common structure that includes the date of the post in the URL. (This seems to be a reasonably well-accepted practice.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the static URLs for permalinks also come static URLs for category archives and feeds. Unfortunately, it looks like I&amp;rsquo;ll have to go back and rework any internal links I created in my own posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I reworked the template to include a hyperlink for adding a post&amp;rsquo;s URL to your &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/&#34;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; bookmarks. Now you can add an entry to your bookmark list with ease!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Current Tech Projects</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/06/current-tech-projects/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2005 14:19:15 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/06/current-tech-projects/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Every now and then, I like to post out here a list of my current &amp;ldquo;tech projects.&amp;rdquo; These are the things that I&amp;rsquo;m working on for my own network, things that I may or may not start recommending to or supporting for customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my current list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;InterNetNews (INN): I had an installation of INN up and running a short while back, but had to resort to an ugly hack with stunnel in order to make SSL work from a newsreader. To get a clean build, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided I&amp;rsquo;ll just start from scratch with a clean installation. I&amp;rsquo;ll be using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.centos.org/&#34;&gt;CentOS&lt;/a&gt; 4.1 again as I work on transitioning all my Linux-based servers to a newer Linux distribution, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be compiling INN from source instead of using a package.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org/&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt;-based antispam gateway: I&amp;rsquo;ve got an antispam gateway running right now (uses Red Hat Linux, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postfix.org/&#34;&gt;Postfix&lt;/a&gt; 2.1, SpamAssassin, Postgrey, Razor, DCC, and ClamAV), but I want to try building one using OpenBSD 3.8 (just recently released) and newer builds of Postfix, SpamAssassin, and Amavisd-New. In particular, I&amp;rsquo;m interested in the advanced integration of newer versions of Postfix and Amavisd-New.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;XC Connect: I&amp;rsquo;ve also mentioned XC Connect before as well, but a previous installation proved to be unstable, and the Apache integration was less than stellar. In fact, the integration was nonexistent. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try a clean build of CentOS 4.1 and XC Connect to see if that will correct the stability and integration problems.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also need to wrap up the documentation for a few completed items, such as the Cisco VPN integration with Active Directory. Mac OS X integration with Active Directory is also on the &amp;ldquo;to do&amp;rdquo; list, but it will have to wait a little while&amp;mdash;I&amp;rsquo;ll need to find another Mac to &amp;ldquo;experiment&amp;rdquo; with instead of using my own PowerBook.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Initial Information on XC Connect</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/30/initial-information-on-xc-connect/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2005 23:24:15 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/30/initial-information-on-xc-connect/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may recall, the idea behind &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xcnetwork.com/&#34;&gt;XC Connect&lt;/a&gt; is that multiple applications across platforms could synchronize data with each other. This would make it possible, for example, for a list of Contacts normally managed inside Outlook to also be shared seamlessly with Linux systems running Evolution and Macintosh clients running iCal. This synchronization would also be possible, in an encrypted fashion, across the Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tests of Windows-to-Windows synchronization are very positive. The but the real test for me is synchronizing between iCal/Address Book and Outlook. If that part works as well as what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen thus far, I will be &lt;strong&gt;truly&lt;/strong&gt; excited. The idea of having a single list of contacts is more enticing than perhaps I can fully elaborate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan on performing some additional tests this weekend, and when those tests are complete I&amp;rsquo;ll post more information here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then all I have to do is figure out why my Treo won&amp;rsquo;t synchronize fully with my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>OK, So Authentication Was Easier Than Expected...</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/11/ok-so-authentication-was-easier-than-expected/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2005 18:10:55 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/11/ok-so-authentication-was-easier-than-expected/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;but SSL is not so easy. I found a workaround for using &lt;a href=&#34;http://stunnel.mirt.net/index.html&#34;&gt;Stunnel&lt;/a&gt;; in order for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.isc.org/products/INN/&#34;&gt;INN&lt;/a&gt; to not think it&amp;rsquo;s another news server feeding it information and instead treat it like a reader, I had to alias another IP address and bind Stunnel on that IP address. It works, but it&amp;rsquo;s not my ideal solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To further complicate matters, it looks like I&amp;rsquo;ll have to compile INN from source myself in order to get SSL support in nnrpd (that&amp;rsquo;s the component that handles connections from NNTP readers). It&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal, I know. It&amp;rsquo;s just my history compiling from source has been a bit rocky.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Authentication and SSL Easier Than Expected</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/09/authentication-and-ssl-easier-than-expected/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2005 00:42:26 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/09/authentication-and-ssl-easier-than-expected/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;My work with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.isc.org/products/INN/&#34;&gt;INN&lt;/a&gt; 2.3.5 as an internal news server is progressing, and I must admit that the configuration of authentication and SSL is going well. Authentication works like a champ, leveraging PAM and therefore automatically leveraging the Kerberos/LDAP integration with Active Directory I implemented a short while ago. The SSL stuff is just a bit trickier; I initially tried the old faithful &lt;a href=&#34;http://stunnel.mirt.net/index.html&#34;&gt;Stunnel&lt;/a&gt;, but found that INN thought the connection was coming from itself and not a reader. That caused INN to respond differently. I&amp;rsquo;ll start looking at native SSL support within INN next, but that can wait until tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Internal News Server Up and Running</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/08/internal-news-server-up-and-running/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2005 20:56:53 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/08/internal-news-server-up-and-running/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally managed to get an internal news server running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.isc.org/index.pl?/sw/inn/&#34;&gt;INN&lt;/a&gt; 2.3.5 up and running, and transferring data from the proprietary platform that is currently hosting some internal newsgroups. I decided to use my first real installation of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.centos.org/&#34;&gt;CentOS&lt;/a&gt; for the internal news server, and so far it has worked out well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a newsfeed to transfer new postings from the proprietary application over to INN, and I&amp;rsquo;m using pullnews right now as I write this to transfer the old articles over. Aside from some limitations and failures which I believe to be the result of the proprietary application&amp;rsquo;s specific implementation of NNTP (which I, personally, feel is another &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/05/14/nonstandard-implementations/&#34;&gt;nonstandard implementation&lt;/a&gt;), everything seems to be transferring over rather well. The next step will be to add authentication to the INN installation, and then add SSL support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more nail in the coffin of a certain proprietary groupware application&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Switched to a New del.icio.us Account</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/25/switched-to-a-new-delicious-account/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2005 15:13:17 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/25/switched-to-a-new-delicious-account/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the process of trying to clean up all the various accounts and subscriptions and what not that I have out there, I have switched to a new &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/&#34;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; account. You can now find my bookmark list at &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/slowe/&#34;&gt;del.icio.us/slowe&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does anyone know how to close an old del.icio.us account?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
