<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/tags/firefox/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-07-13 15:51:12 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Firefox Updates and Roadmap</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/13/firefox-updates-and-roadmap/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2005 15:51:12 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/13/firefox-updates-and-roadmap/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Mozilla released &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; 1.0.5, which patches a number of security vulnerabilities. You can get more information on the release &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1836310,00.asp&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or by visiting the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org&#34;&gt;Mozilla.org&lt;/a&gt; web site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1895,1821168,00.asp&#34;&gt;more information&lt;/a&gt; has been revealed about Firefox 1.1, the next version of the open source web browser. An alpha version of Firefox 1.1 could be ready within just a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Mozilla can continue to innovate with Firefox and address my two primary concerns&amp;ndash;ease of deployment and distributing security updates&amp;ndash;then they will continue to steal market share away from Internet Explorer. If nothing else, Mozilla will at least force Microsoft to be competitive again, and that is a success in and of itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mozilla is also updating &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/products/thunderbird&#34;&gt;Thunderbird&lt;/a&gt;, the companion e-mail client to Firefox, and that update is expected to be available soon as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Watch Out, IE Users</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/01/watch-out-ie-users/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 17:32:09 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/01/watch-out-ie-users/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of articles are highlighting a recently uncovered security flaw in Microsoft Internet Explorer&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1833697,00.asp&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;eWeek&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computerworld.com/securitytopics/security/story/0,10801,102924,00.html&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;ComputerWorld&lt;/em&gt;, both of which reference this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/technet/security/advisory/903144.mspx&#34;&gt;security advisory&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fix is to set the Security Level for the Internet Zone to High, which disables the functionality required for the exploit to work. Unfortunately, it also disables a lot of other things that non-malicious sites use, so this workaround will affect your ordinary browsing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recommendation is to switch to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/&#34;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt;. While Firefox was shown to be vulnerable to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1830025,00.asp&#34;&gt;recent spoofing flaw&lt;/a&gt; (this flaw also affected IE, Safari, Camino, etc.), it&amp;rsquo;s still better than IE&amp;rsquo;s security record. And, yes, for those of you out there who are yelling at your computer screens right now: I know that you probably believe that Firefox is only more secure because there are fewer people using it. Perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s true, but the end result is that it&amp;rsquo;s more secure. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that what we are seeking to achieve?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
