<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/tags/virtualization/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-12-26 21:45:32 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Security Flaw Found in VMware</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/26/security-flaw-found-in-vmware/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2005 21:45:32 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/26/security-flaw-found-in-vmware/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Just so the Windows flaws don&amp;rsquo;t get all the attention, here&amp;rsquo;s a reasonably new one: a flaw in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;, the machine virtualization software that is tremendously popular, especially among security professionals. Fortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s reasonably easy to work around the flaw, and VMware has already released a patch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This link offers more details on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1904647,00.asp&#34;&gt;VMware security flaw&lt;/a&gt;, which apparently affects almost all of the VMware products, with the notable exception of ESX Server. VMware&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/support/kb/enduser/std_adp.php?p_faqid=2000&#34;&gt;security advisory&lt;/a&gt; also provides complete details and information on how to protect against it, plus a link to download the patch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VMware users can sidestep the security issue by not using NAT networking for their virtual machines, as pointed out in the security advisory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While security flaws in Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Windows operating system and Internet Explorer web browser get most of the attention these days, all products have them. Users of Linux or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; like to proclaim their immunity, but no one is immune. This recent vulnerability merely highlights the fact that we must all be vigilant and watchful in order to maintain the security and integrity of our networks and systems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>OpenBSD pcn0 Driver Issue Resolved</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/04/openbsd-pcn0-driver-issue-resolved/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2005 08:48:20 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/04/openbsd-pcn0-driver-issue-resolved/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, sort of resolved. I was never able to make the &lt;code&gt;pcn&lt;/code&gt; driver (from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org/&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; 3.8) actually work under &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;, but I did find information on how to disable the &lt;code&gt;pcn&lt;/code&gt; driver and revert to the older &lt;code&gt;le&lt;/code&gt; driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://archives.neohapsis.com/archives/openbsd/2005-08/1314.html&#34;&gt;archived Neohapsis discussion&lt;/a&gt;, followed by a quick e-mail exchange with the author of the thread (who, thankfully, was very responsive and very helpful) led me to the solution. Some of it I had to improvise on the fly, but here&amp;rsquo;s the overall process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boot from the OpenBSD 3.8 boot CD image (I pointed the virtual CD-ROM drive in the VM directly to the corresponding ISO image).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the OpenBSD &amp;ldquo;boot&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo; prompt, type &amp;ldquo;-c&amp;rdquo; and press Enter. This takes you into User Kernel Config, or UKC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the UKC prompt, type &amp;ldquo;disable pcn&amp;rdquo; to disable the &lt;code&gt;pcn&lt;/code&gt; driver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type &amp;ldquo;quit&amp;rdquo; at the next UKC prompt to exit the kernel config and proceed with the boot process. If you watch the boot process, you will see OpenBSD load the &lt;code&gt;le&lt;/code&gt; driver and identify the virtual NIC as &lt;code&gt;le1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all well and good, but how do you make the changes stick between reboots? Here&amp;rsquo;s how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve gotten OpenBSD fully installed and are rebooting for the first time after installation, follow the steps above to use the &lt;code&gt;le&lt;/code&gt; driver for the next reboot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the &amp;ldquo;config -e -o nbsd bsd&amp;rdquo; command (see the relevant &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi?query=config&amp;amp;apropos=0&amp;amp;sektion=0&amp;amp;manpath=OpenBSD+3.8&amp;amp;arch=i386&amp;amp;format=html&#34;&gt;man page&lt;/a&gt; for details) to modify the kernel again, only this time saving the changes to the file named &amp;ldquo;nbsd&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon the next reboot after using the config command to create a new kernel file, specify the name of that new kernel file (&amp;ldquo;nbsd&amp;rdquo; in our example here) at the OpenBSD &amp;ldquo;boot&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo; prompt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assuming that everything works OK (it did for me), rename the original kernel to &amp;ldquo;bsd.original&amp;rdquo; and rename your new kernel to just &amp;ldquo;bsd&amp;rdquo;. Then, upon the next reboot, the &lt;code&gt;pcn&lt;/code&gt; driver should be disabled and everything should work just fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this process, I now have two OpenBSD 3.8 VMs running and haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced any issues. Now, on to installing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clamav.net/&#34;&gt;ClamAV&lt;/a&gt; on OpenBSD&amp;hellip;.&lt;em&gt;(more details soon)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;code&gt;pcn0&lt;/code&gt; network driver from OpenBSD 3.9 works perfectly under VMware (at least, on ESX Server). I have posted more information &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2006/05/18/openbsd-39-on-esx-server/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Running Windows Apps on an Intel-Based Mac</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/26/running-windows-apps-on-an-intel-based-mac/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2005 16:36:17 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/26/running-windows-apps-on-an-intel-based-mac/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting side effect of Apple&amp;rsquo;s announcement to move the Macintosh platform to Intel-based CPUs: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeweavers.com/&#34;&gt;CodeWeavers&lt;/a&gt; has announced that they will expand their services and products to include the new Intel-based Macs (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://business.newsforge.com/article.pl?sid=05/06/24/1530234&amp;amp;from=rss&#34;&gt;CodeWeavers sees Mactel move as an opportunity&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newsforge.com/&#34;&gt;NewsForge&lt;/a&gt; site). More information is also available in the official CodeWeavers &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeweavers.com/about/general/press/?id=20050622&#34;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very good thing. If CodeWeavers is successful in making a version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeweavers.com/products/cxoffice/&#34;&gt;CrossOver Office&lt;/a&gt; to run on the Intel-based Macs, it will make it easier to users to choose whatever platform best suits their needs, be it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;, Linux, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;. They won&amp;rsquo;t feel tied to a specific platform just because there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; application they need that only runs on &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; specific platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I use Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/mac/products/virtualpc/virtualpc.aspx&#34;&gt;Virtual PC for the Mac&lt;/a&gt; to run any Windows-specific programs I need. This works reasonably well, but takes a performance hit because it has to emulate an Intel-compatible CPU. With Intel-based CPUs under the hood already, Virtual PC (or CrossOver Office, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/Research/SRG/netos/xen/&#34;&gt;Xen&lt;/a&gt;, or any other emulation software) will practically fly. This makes emulation a much more attractive option than it is right now. That, in turn, means more choice and more freedom for end users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Virtualization</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/26/virtualization/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2005 16:01:32 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/26/virtualization/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtualization/&#34;&gt;virtualization&lt;/a&gt;. I love the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt; products (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/desktop/ws_features.html&#34;&gt;VMware Workstation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/server/gsx_features.html&#34;&gt;GSX Server&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/server/esx_features.html&#34;&gt;ESX Server&lt;/a&gt;) and, as I have mentioned in previous posts, use Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/mac/products/virtualpc/virtualpc.aspx&#34;&gt;Virtual PC&lt;/a&gt; product currently (but only because VMware doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a Mac version of VMware Workstation). I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to hardware-based virtualization technologies such as AMD&amp;rsquo;s Pacifica (discussed briefly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1780606,00.asp&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1820551,00.asp&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and Intel&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intel.com/technology/computing/vptech/&#34;&gt;Vanderpool&lt;/a&gt; technology. I&amp;rsquo;m very much hoping that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; will take the plunge and build in virtualization support in Mac OS X 10.5, aka &amp;ldquo;Leopard&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtualization is more than just running multiple operating systems on a single computer, though. Virtualization occurs in networking through the use of virtual LANs (VLANs) and virtual private networks (VPNs); both of these technologies are core technologies in today&amp;rsquo;s flexible networks. Virtualization occurs in storage area networks (SANs) as virtual disks and virtual SANs (VSANs). Technologies such as load balancing via virtual servers (recently read an interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://software.newsforge.com/article.pl?sid=05/05/27/0612243&#34;&gt;article on Linux virtual servers&lt;/a&gt;) also employ a form of virtualization. Even mundane technologies such as network address translation (NAT) can be considered forms of virtualization, since they abstract a server&amp;rsquo;s public IP address from its private (actual) IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As IT professionals, it behooves us to embrace new technologies like virtualization, in all its forms. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already taken the time to get used to these kinds of products and technologies, now might be a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
