<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/categories/macintosh/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-11-29 17:38:01 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Market-speak</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/market-speak/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 17:38:01 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/market-speak/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I found &lt;a href=&#34;http://ideastorm.com/blog/2005/11/29/market-speak/&#34;&gt;this little post&lt;/a&gt; while searching over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/&#34;&gt;Technorati&lt;/a&gt;. How true!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>ipfw Rules for Bonjour</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/28/ipfw-rules-for-bonjour/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2005 16:11:38 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/28/ipfw-rules-for-bonjour/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I originally published this information on my business website, but thought I&amp;rsquo;d reproduce it here in the event someone needs it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/bonjour/&#34;&gt;Bonjour&lt;/a&gt; (formerly Rendezvous) auto-discovery service is used in a number of Apple-branded products as well as a growing number of third-party applications (for example, my HP Color LaserJet 2550N supports Bonjour). It&amp;rsquo;s used to advertise and discover &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/itunes/&#34;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; music libraries, and Apple&amp;rsquo;s Airport Admin Utility also uses Bonjour to discover &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/airportextreme/&#34;&gt;Airport Extreme&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/airportexpress/&#34;&gt;Airport Express&lt;/a&gt; wireless base stations for configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonjour uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multicastdns.org/&#34;&gt;multicast DNS&lt;/a&gt; (known as mDNS), part of the IETF standard known as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeroconf.org/&#34;&gt;Zeroconf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that is well and good, but if you are using the built-in firewall you most likely are preventing Bonjour from working correctly. I grew frustrated trying to utilize Bonjour-related services while also keeping my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/powerbook/&#34;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/a&gt; protected against unwanted network traffic. Using a packet sniffer and Brian Hill&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://personalpages.tds.net/~brian_hill/brickhouse.html&#34;&gt;Brickhouse&lt;/a&gt; application, I observed Bonjour traffic and created a set of ipfw rules that can be used to allow this traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multicast DNS operates over UDP (IP protocol 17) with a destination port 5353 and a source port above 1024. The destination address is, of course, a multicast address (in the 224.0.0.0 range). Responses to mDNS multicasts originate from UDP port 5353, but are bound for a random high port above 1024. Simply defining a rule that allows traffic to and from UDP port 5353 wont work, because while outbound traffic will be correctly matched the responses to those outbound requests wont be matched and will be dropped (assuming the default action is to deny traffic). So, a sample rule to be added to ipfw might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;add 2008 allow udp from 10.1.1.0/24 5353 to any 1024-65535 in via en0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This should be entered all on a single line.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This rule allows traffic from the source network 10.1.1.0 (the &amp;ldquo;/24&amp;rdquo; indicating a 24-bit mask, i.e., a subnet mask of 255.255.255.0) from UDP source port 5353 to any port above 1024 on any destination address inbound via the en0 interface. The en0 interface is typically the built-in Ethernet interface on most &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;-based systems. (Likewise, en1 is typically the built-in AirPort/AirPort Extreme wireless interface.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are tightly restricting outbound traffic as well, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a matching outbound rule (of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own experience has shown that adding this rule to my ipfw ruleset has allowed Bonjour to work as expected without sacrificing the security of my system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Making Backup DVD Copies</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/27/making-backup-dvd-copies/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2005 20:23:16 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/27/making-backup-dvd-copies/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I love DVDs. Ever since I bought my surround sound system around Christmas of 2000, I have preferred DVDs over VHS for any new movies that we purchase. The big problem, though, is that DVDs aren&amp;rsquo;t nearly as durable as videotapes, and in a family with kids that&amp;rsquo;s a big deal. I have younger kids, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t take much for a kid to scratch a DVD when putting it into or taking it out of the DVD player. All it takes is one scratch and that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the end of that movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before I switched to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;, I have been making digital copies of every CD that I purchase, so that I can quickly and easily make another copy in the event that the original CD gets damaged in any way. The introduction of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/itunes/&#34;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; and my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/ipod/&#34;&gt;iPod&lt;/a&gt; have made this easier. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t considered, even with the introduction of the 5th generation iPod with video capabilities, that I could do the same with my DVDs until just the other day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I set out to see if it was possible to do the same with my DVDs. I&amp;rsquo;d researched this a little bit earlier, so I already knew about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.losprimates.net/mtr/&#34;&gt;MacTheRipper&lt;/a&gt; (MTR), a program for extracting the digital video from a DVD. I used MTR to extract the video for &lt;em&gt;I, Robot&lt;/em&gt; to an external FireWire hard drive attached to my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/powerbook/&#34;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/a&gt;. That process went well, didn&amp;rsquo;t take too terribly long, and the resulting VIDEO_TS folder created by MTR worked flawlessly using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.videolan.org/vlc/&#34;&gt;VLC&lt;/a&gt;. I then turned to a program called &lt;a href=&#34;http://lonestar.utsa.edu/llee/applescript/dvdimager.html&#34;&gt;DVD Imager&lt;/a&gt;, which is designed to turn a VIDEO_TS folder into a DVD image that can be burned to a DVD. The problem, however, was that the VIDEO_TS folder and the resulting DVD image were 6.87GB in size. As a result, I was not able to burn the image back to a standard DVD-R using my PowerBook&amp;rsquo;s SuperDrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried another DVD (&lt;em&gt;Robots&lt;/em&gt; this time) and ended up with 4.62GB of data. OK, I thought, a single-layer DVD holds 4.7GB of data so I should be fine. Wrong! That didn&amp;rsquo;t work, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That means I&amp;rsquo;m currently stumped as to the next step. A number of online searches have turned up recommendations for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.roxio.com/en/products/popcorn/&#34;&gt;Popcorn&lt;/a&gt; (from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.roxio.com/&#34;&gt;Roxio&lt;/a&gt;), but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to see if I can avoid having to purchase software and instead make do with freeware and/or open source applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Open Source on Mac OS X</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/06/open-source-on-mac-os-x/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2005 12:04:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/06/open-source-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people automatically equate &amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo; with Linux or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache&lt;/a&gt;. But there&amp;rsquo;s more to open source than that. There are a wide variety of open source projects that are also targeted at (gasp) &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Windows&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a Mac user myself, I was particularly interested in &lt;a href=&#34;http://software.newsforge.com/article.pl?sid=05/09/20/166254&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; recently posted at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newsforge.com/&#34;&gt;NewsForge&lt;/a&gt;. Some of the projects listed there were new to me; for example, I had never heard of or used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opencommunity.co.uk/vienna2.html&#34;&gt;Vienna&lt;/a&gt;. Given that I don&amp;rsquo;t like brushed metal interfaces (can&amp;rsquo;t stand them) and that I already use a commercial RSS reader, Vienna won&amp;rsquo;t do me much good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the projects listed there, though, I was familiar with and actually using currently. For example, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adiumx.com/&#34;&gt;Adium X&lt;/a&gt; is my default IM client (I use it to stay connected to MSN, AIM, and Google Talk), &lt;a href=&#34;http://cyberduck.ch/&#34;&gt;Cyberduck&lt;/a&gt; is my FTP/SFTP client, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://growl.info/&#34;&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; helps keep me informed about what is happening with all the various applications I have running. I&amp;rsquo;ve never used &lt;a href=&#34;http://seashore.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Seashore&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have a look at it soon (I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a good image editor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nothickmanuals.info/doku.php?id=opensourcemac&#34;&gt;This link&lt;/a&gt; (also referenced in the NewsForge article) lists an even larger variety of open source Mac applications. Again, some I recognize (and use), a lot that I don&amp;rsquo;t. If you are a Mac user, I encourage you to take another look at some of the many high-quality open source projects available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Moving Back to Desktop Manager</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/04/moving-back-to-desktop-manager/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2005 09:00:32 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/04/moving-back-to-desktop-manager/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few days or so, I have been experimenting with &lt;a href=&#34;http://virtuedesktops.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Virtue&lt;/a&gt;, a virtual desktop application. I&amp;rsquo;ve used various virtual desktop applications since switching to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/09/30/virtual-desktops-on-mac-os-x/&#34;&gt;this blog posting&lt;/a&gt;). After getting used to the lack of a desktop pager, I was really beginning to like Virtue and it&amp;rsquo;s functionality, even though it seemed as though the Virtue project had slowed and/or stopped development. Finally, after searching around for some way of re-instating the &amp;ldquo;Run Application&amp;rdquo; feature in &lt;a href=&#34;http://desktopmanager.berlios.de/&#34;&gt;Desktop Manager&lt;/a&gt;, I found that Virtue was incompatible with Mac OS X 10.4, aka &amp;ldquo;Tiger.&amp;rdquo; Since I&amp;rsquo;ve been researching the possibility of an upgrade to Tiger, I decided I&amp;rsquo;d better switch back to an application that was supposed to run under Tiger (which, based on what I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to find, Desktop Manager does).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a real shame, too. Virtue has a great feature set (I love the idea of the &amp;ldquo;primitives,&amp;rdquo; which are text and/or colors that can be applied to individual desktops). I didn&amp;rsquo;t use the per-desktop wallpaper functionality or the per-desktop icons, but I know a few people whose desktop-centric filing system would have really loved those features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were a programmer, I&amp;rsquo;d probably pick up the code myself and run with it. But I&amp;rsquo;m not, so there you go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Virtual Desktops on Mac OS X</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/30/virtual-desktops-on-mac-os-x/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2005 22:15:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/30/virtual-desktops-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost from the moment I switched to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;, I started looking for an application to provide the functionality of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_desktop&#34;&gt;virtual desktops&lt;/a&gt;. I suppose my days of dabbling with Linux and the X Window System had ingrained me to believe that a *nix-based system just wasn&amp;rsquo;t the same without virtual desktops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My virtual desktop journey started with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codetek.com/ctvd/&#34;&gt;CodeTek Virtual Desktop&lt;/a&gt;, a commercial product that&amp;rsquo;s very capable. The idea of the desktop pager was very natural, and the ability to automatically switch desktops when switching applications was very handy. I could simply Alt-Tab to the application I needed and CodeTek would automatically switch the appropriate desktop. I could also specify that new windows for a particular application should always be created on a particular desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, I started looking into a new crop of open source virtual desktop managers. &lt;a href=&#34;http://space.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Space.app&lt;/a&gt; was one, but was (granted, this was quite some time ago) still a bit too rough around the edges. I was then turned on to &lt;a href=&#34;http://desktopmanager.berlios.de/&#34;&gt;Desktop Manager&lt;/a&gt;, which I used for long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desktop Manager wasn&amp;rsquo;t as full-featured in some aspects as CTVD, but I really liked the desktop transitions (great way to show off Mac OS X&amp;rsquo;s graphics functionality). The ability to support CTVD pager skins was a nice feature as well, and I really like the overlay of the desktop name on the desktop. One feature that I particularly enjoyed using was the Mac equivalent of the Run dialog box, invoked by Option-Cmd-R. This made it easy to launch an application without having to navigate to the desktop where the Applications folder was found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just within the last day or so, I started using &lt;a href=&#34;http://virtuedesktops.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Virtue&lt;/a&gt;. Virtue&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;claim to fame&amp;rdquo; is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t use a desktop pager to switch virtual desktops; instead, it uses a translucent pop-up window similar to that used by &lt;a href=&#34;http://quicksilver.blacktree.com/&#34;&gt;Quicksilver&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m having a bit of a problem getting used to the lack of a desktop pager, but the pop-up bezel is kind of cool, and it looks as if Virtue supports different wallpapers for different desktops. Virtue also appears to be more advanced with regards to applying desktop overlays (like the desktop name, for example). All in all, it looks like a great application. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ll stay with it or not; if I do switch back to Desktop Manager, it will be simply because I am too ingrained to use the desktop pager and because I miss my &amp;ldquo;Run&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; keyboard shortcut. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give it an honest try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Another Switcher to the Mac</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/22/another-switcher-to-the-mac/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2005 21:12:15 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/22/another-switcher-to-the-mac/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In reading through a pile of unread industry magazines, I came across an article by Kevin Tolly, a columnist for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.networkworld.com/&#34;&gt;Network World&lt;/a&gt;, titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.networkworld.com/columnists/2005/091205tolly.html&#34;&gt;Closing the door on Windows&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, that describes his switch to the Macintosh platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess my own personal switch from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; last year was, to borrow a phrase from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.infoworld.com/columnists/tom_curve.html&#34;&gt;Tom Yager&lt;/a&gt;, ahead of the curve. In his article, Tolly describes the experience in these terms (all content copyright of respective holders):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;the bottom line is that I&amp;rsquo;m able to get my work done more efficiently with fewer crashes and have already found &amp;lsquo;richer&amp;rsquo; programs&amp;hellip;which I expect to offer me more than their MS Office counterparts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I can&amp;rsquo;t vouch for the latter part of his statement (I don&amp;rsquo;t use Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/iwork/&#34;&gt;iWork&lt;/a&gt; suite), I can say that my own experience is much the same. The Mac&amp;rsquo;s fluid UI, rock-solid BSD underpinnings, pervasive networking support, and a variety of open source applications make it possible for me to do my job in a very effective manner. That&amp;rsquo;s not to say that everyone will have the same result, but it is definitely to say that the Mac is a viable alternative. It is &lt;strong&gt;definitely&lt;/strong&gt; a viable alternative, and more and more people are discovering that fact.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Very Handy Add-On</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/04/very-handy-add-on/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2005 22:57:42 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/04/very-handy-add-on/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I just found a &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;very&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; handy add-on for Mac OS X. It&amp;rsquo;s called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.xutils.com/rdcmenu/&#34;&gt;RDC Menu&lt;/a&gt; and it is a tool that provides an easy way of launching multiple instances of Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/mac/otherproducts/otherproducts.aspx?pid=remotedesktopclient&#34;&gt;Remote Desktop Connection&lt;/a&gt; application for the Mac. If you manage Windows-based networks, you already know how useful Remote Desktop Connection (RDC) is, but the one key flaw in RDC was that you couldn&amp;rsquo;t launch multiple instances and thus couldn&amp;rsquo;t be connected to more than one Windows computer at a time. With RDC Menu, all that changes. Working as either a Dock item or as a Menu Extra, it allows you to easily launch multiple instances of RDC to connect to multiple Windows-based systems. I run RDC Menu as a Dock item (I don&amp;rsquo;t like too many Menu Extras).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Modifying Camino&#39;s Exceptions List for Cookies</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/13/modifying-caminos-exceptions-list-for-cookies/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2005 22:36:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/13/modifying-caminos-exceptions-list-for-cookies/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a stickler about cookies. No, not the kind you eat&amp;hellip;the kind that web servers place on your computer when you visit a web site. I understand that cookies are sometimes necessary to maintain state as a user navigates through a web site; HTTP is, after all, a stateless protocol. But a cookie for every site no matter what? That just gets on my nerves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Up until now, I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org/&#34;&gt;Camino&lt;/a&gt; configured to ask if I wanted to allow a cookie or not. This got time-consuming when I was visiting a site I had never visited before and all the ad servers wanted to place a cookie to track me. I wanted a way to tell Camino, &amp;ldquo;Block all cookies unless I say otherwise.&amp;rdquo; Finally, in Camino 0.9a1, I can set all cookies to be denied and then view the exception list, but there was still no way to edit the exception list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being the determined (read: stubborn) person that I am, I was determined to find a way to edit this exceptions list. (As a side note to the Camino developers, please write a UI for editing the exception list.) After not too much searching, I found that the &lt;code&gt;hostperm.1&lt;/code&gt; file in &lt;code&gt;~/Library/Application Support/Camino&lt;/code&gt; is an ordinary text file that contains the exceptions list. To add a site to this list, simply follow the same format as one of the existing lines, specifying 1 to allow cookies or 2 to deny cookies. Of course, any editing to this file should be done while Camino is not running.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Bonjour (The Technology, Not the Greeting)</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/11/bonjour-the-technology-not-the-greeting/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2005 23:39:46 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/11/bonjour-the-technology-not-the-greeting/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the RSS feeds from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macosxhints.com&#34;&gt;Mac OS X Hints&lt;/a&gt; today pointed me to a website on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dns-sd.org/&#34;&gt;DNS Service Discovery (DNS-SD)&lt;/a&gt;. DNS-SD is part of the magic behind &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/bonjour/&#34;&gt;Bonjour&lt;/a&gt; (formerly named Rendezvous), the way in which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; is able to automatically locate services across the network. Bonjour is used, for example, in locating an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/airportextreme/&#34;&gt;Airport Extreme&lt;/a&gt; base station, or used by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org&#34;&gt;Camino&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/safari/&#34;&gt;Safari&lt;/a&gt; to find web servers on your network. Personally, I like Bonjour, and it&amp;rsquo;s good to see that it is finally being extended beyond single-segment implementations. And, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://a1408.g.akamai.net/7/1408/9955/20050505/akamai.info.apple.com/Bonjour/061-1768.20050505.BJWdw/BonjourSetup.exe&#34;&gt;Bonjour for Windows&lt;/a&gt; available from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s starting to look like a viable cross-platform solution for finding and connecting to network services automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Camino&#39;s Latest Iteration</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/11/caminos-latest-iteration/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2005 23:24:29 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/11/caminos-latest-iteration/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org&#34;&gt;Camino 0.9a1&lt;/a&gt;, the latest version of the native &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; browser, for the last few days. I have to say that I am impressed. I like the new features on the Go menu that shows the most recently visited websites; this makes it easier to flip back to a site than having to switch to the &amp;ldquo;Bookmarks&amp;rdquo; view. The new tab bar is much better as well; I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stand the old one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nada.de/mac/camitools/&#34;&gt;CamiTools&lt;/a&gt; add-ons for Camino 0.9a1 are also excellent; I&amp;rsquo;m using both CamiOptions as well as CamiFlash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are using Camino now, you should give this new version a spin. You&amp;rsquo;ll be glad you did.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Stupid Tricks With The Mac OS X Firewall</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/07/stupid-tricks-with-the-mac-os-x-firewall/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2005 22:54:40 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/07/stupid-tricks-with-the-mac-os-x-firewall/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting way to block access to your &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; system. Simply modify your ipfw script to block traffic to or from the 127.0.0.0/8 network. When you do this, your Mac will simply fail to log you in, instead presenting you with an endless spinning disk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only workaround is to hold down the Shift key while booting (to initiate a Safe Boot), then disable the StartupItem that launches and configures the firewall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I speak from personal experience, having added the aforementioned rules in an effort to block spoofed traffic from accessing the loopback interface. Apparently, Mac OS X is different enough from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freebsd.org/&#34;&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt; that this advice (advocated on a couple of FreeBSD-related sites I found while searching for ipfw information) is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>YAMB (Yet Another Mac Browser)</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/05/yamb-yet-another-mac-browser/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2005 16:33:03 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/05/yamb-yet-another-mac-browser/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the title may indicate otherwise, I&amp;rsquo;m actually glad to see more browsers popping up for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;. Choice is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new kid on the block this time is &lt;a href=&#34;http://hmdt-web.net/shiira/index-e.html&#34;&gt;Shiira&lt;/a&gt;, a WebKit-based browser that offers some pretty useful features. These features include Tab Expose, which is Expose for browser tabs (activated via F8); &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growl.info/&#34;&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; integration; integration with Safari Bookmarks; and a clean, native Aqua interface. Because it uses Apple&amp;rsquo;s WebKit (now open sourced and available &lt;a href=&#34;http://webkit.opendarwin.org/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), it renders pages the same way as Safari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like some features about Shiira (especially the Growl integration and the tabbed browsing implementation), but still find myself going back to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org/&#34;&gt;Camino&lt;/a&gt;. A new alpha version of Camino 0.9 has been released, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t brought myself to use it yet. If Camino had a way to provide notifications via Growl (I&amp;rsquo;d really like for my browser to notify me when a download is complete), I would be just absolutely thrilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Shiira is an open source project, released under a BSD style license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Running Windows Apps on an Intel-Based Mac</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/26/running-windows-apps-on-an-intel-based-mac/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2005 16:36:17 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/26/running-windows-apps-on-an-intel-based-mac/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting side effect of Apple&amp;rsquo;s announcement to move the Macintosh platform to Intel-based CPUs: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeweavers.com/&#34;&gt;CodeWeavers&lt;/a&gt; has announced that they will expand their services and products to include the new Intel-based Macs (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://business.newsforge.com/article.pl?sid=05/06/24/1530234&amp;amp;from=rss&#34;&gt;CodeWeavers sees Mactel move as an opportunity&lt;/a&gt; on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newsforge.com/&#34;&gt;NewsForge&lt;/a&gt; site). More information is also available in the official CodeWeavers &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeweavers.com/about/general/press/?id=20050622&#34;&gt;press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a very good thing. If CodeWeavers is successful in making a version of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeweavers.com/products/cxoffice/&#34;&gt;CrossOver Office&lt;/a&gt; to run on the Intel-based Macs, it will make it easier to users to choose whatever platform best suits their needs, be it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt;, Linux, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;. They won&amp;rsquo;t feel tied to a specific platform just because there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; application they need that only runs on &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; specific platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I use Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/mac/products/virtualpc/virtualpc.aspx&#34;&gt;Virtual PC for the Mac&lt;/a&gt; to run any Windows-specific programs I need. This works reasonably well, but takes a performance hit because it has to emulate an Intel-compatible CPU. With Intel-based CPUs under the hood already, Virtual PC (or CrossOver Office, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cl.cam.ac.uk/Research/SRG/netos/xen/&#34;&gt;Xen&lt;/a&gt;, or any other emulation software) will practically fly. This makes emulation a much more attractive option than it is right now. That, in turn, means more choice and more freedom for end users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Why I Use a Mac</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/20/why-i-use-a-mac/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 21:21:10 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/20/why-i-use-a-mac/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A fair number of people have asked me why I use an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/hardware/&#34;&gt;Apple Mac&lt;/a&gt; when my business centers primarily around &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; products such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windowsserver2003/&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2003&lt;/a&gt;, Active Directory, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/&#34;&gt;Exchange&lt;/a&gt;? That&amp;rsquo;s a reasonable question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My computer is simply a tool to get my job done. About two years ago, I started to evaluate the tasks that I tackle on a regular basis as part of supporting my customers&amp;rsquo; networks. In reviewing those tasks, it become evident to me that using Windows myself was not a prerequisite for designing, installing, and supporting Windows-based networks. I could run a different OS&amp;ndash;like Linux or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;and still be perfectly able to get my job done. In fact, given that I wanted to increase the amount of work that my company did with open source software such as Linux, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postfix.org/&#34;&gt;Postfix&lt;/a&gt;, and SpamAssassin, something other than Windows might actually make that &lt;em&gt;easier&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then set out to compare the alternatives. After comparing Linux and Mac OS X, I found that Mac OS X had the best fit for &lt;em&gt;my&lt;/em&gt; particular needs. I loved the mix of open source technologies (the BSD underpinnings and various other open source projects) and closed software (the ultrasmooth Aqua interface). I loved the hardware. And, most importantly, I found that there were applications available for Mac OS X to help me get my job done. (See my blog posting about &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/06/20/preferred-mac-os-x-applications/&#34;&gt;Preferred Mac OS X Applications&lt;/a&gt;.) The fact that many of the applications I needed for my job were open source applications was a bonus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is Mac OS X right for you? I don&amp;rsquo;t know; that depends upon what you do at your job. I believe that Mac OS X is a great fit for more people than Windows, but I also believe that people must use what is most ideally suited for their work. If that is Windows; so be it. If that is Linux, then great. And if, like me, it is Mac OS X, then fantastic. Each of these operating systems have their own strengths and weaknesses, and it is up to each user to determine which OS is right for them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Preferred Mac OS X Applications</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/20/preferred-mac-os-x-applications/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 00:36:34 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/20/preferred-mac-os-x-applications/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I suppose I should go ahead and post the obligatory list of preferred &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; applications. So, without further ado, here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SFTP Client:&lt;/em&gt; I used to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://rsug.itd.umich.edu/software/fugu/&#34;&gt;Fugu&lt;/a&gt;, but switched not too long ago to &lt;a href=&#34;http://cyberduck.ch/&#34;&gt;Cyberduck&lt;/a&gt;. I like Cyberduck&amp;rsquo;s Synchronize feature (to keep local and remote directories synchronized) and the built-in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growl.info/&#34;&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; support. I still keep Fugu around, but don&amp;rsquo;t use it nearly as much as I did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Web Browser:&lt;/em&gt; I primarily use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org/&#34;&gt;Camino&lt;/a&gt;, although I will use Safari from time to time. I know that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; is available in a Mac OS X version, but I just prefer Camino.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Usenet Client:&lt;/em&gt; I tried a couple of open source applications, but finally settled on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.panic.com/unison/&#34;&gt;Unison&lt;/a&gt;. My only complaint with Unison is that I can&amp;rsquo;t post a message to a newsgroup and send a copy of the message to someone&amp;rsquo;s e-mail address at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;RSS Reader:&lt;/em&gt; Again, I tried a couple different applications (like &lt;a href=&#34;http://ranchero.com/netnewswire/&#34;&gt;NetNewsWire Lite&lt;/a&gt;) but was most satisfied with &lt;a href=&#34;http://freshsqueeze.com/products/pulpfiction/&#34;&gt;PulpFiction&lt;/a&gt;. The Mail.app-like interface and built-in Growl support fit my work habits well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instant Messaging:&lt;/em&gt; The open source &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adiumx.com/index.php&#34;&gt;Adium&lt;/a&gt; client won my heart, although &lt;a href=&#34;http://fire.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Fire&lt;/a&gt; was a very close second.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Organization:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.omnigroup.com/applications/omnioutliner/&#34;&gt;OmniOutliner&lt;/a&gt; is a great application, very versatile and very flexible. I&amp;rsquo;ve found numerous uses for it so far, and expect that I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to find more and more ways to use this application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Miscellaneous Applications:&lt;/em&gt; These applications defy any sort of categorization. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growl.info/&#34;&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; notification system, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ecto.kung-foo.tv/&#34;&gt;ecto&lt;/a&gt; blogging client, &lt;a href=&#34;http://desktopmanager.berlios.de/&#34;&gt;Desktop Manager&lt;/a&gt; virtual desktop application, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scifihifi.com/cocoalicious/&#34;&gt;Cocoalicious&lt;/a&gt; del.icio.us client all have a home on my PowerBook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I can&amp;rsquo;t live without &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/mac/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Office&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/ical/&#34;&gt;iCal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/isync/&#34;&gt;iSync&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.omnigroup.com/applications/omnigraffle/&#34;&gt;OmniGraffle&lt;/a&gt;, and others. This list should at least get things started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>del.icio.us Client</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/delicious-client/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 13:49:37 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/delicious-client/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of you probably use &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/&#34;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt;, or have at least heard of it. You may not have heard of a native &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; client for del.icio.us called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scifihifi.com/cocoalicious/&#34;&gt;Cocoalicious&lt;/a&gt;. If you use del.icio.us and Mac OS X, you should give this application a try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Apple on Intel</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/apple-on-intel/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 13:41:02 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/apple-on-intel/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was away in Florida on vacation, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; announced at WWDC 2005 that they will transition to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intel.com/&#34;&gt;Intel&lt;/a&gt; CPUs over the next couple of years. I won&amp;rsquo;t try to predict what this will mean, or whether Apple will go away, or anything deep like that. It makes perfect sense from a hardware perspective; Apple needs faster CPUs because the whole theme of &amp;ldquo;processor speed doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter&amp;rdquo; just isn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it with the masses. The ordinary John and Jane Doe out there don&amp;rsquo;t know that a 2.5GHz G5 is as equally powerful as a 3.6GHz Pentium 4. They just know that the Pentium 4 is faster, and that means the system is better, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/powerbook/&#34;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;, not for the PowerPC CPU inside. Did the PowerPC G4 processor add an era of mystique, of uniqueness? Sure. In the end, however, I bought a PowerBook because I liked Mac OS X and because I could get the applications I needed to get my work done on a Mac. If I can do that with an Intel-powered Mac that is just as fast or faster, then so be it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Truth be told, I do worry about Apple&amp;rsquo;s hardware business, though, and what this will mean for them. Time will tell.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
