<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/tags/networking/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-12-23 14:50:45 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>CentOS NTPd Problem (Mostly) Resolved</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/23/centos-ntpd-problem-mostly-resolved/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2005 14:50:45 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/23/centos-ntpd-problem-mostly-resolved/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The NTPd problem that I &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/08/16/strange-ntpd-problem-on-centos-41/&#34;&gt;wrestled with in CentOS 4.1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/12/19/ntpd-on-centos-42/&#34;&gt;again in CentOS 4.2&lt;/a&gt; has finally been resolved. Mostly. I think. The specific steps I took to resolve the issue came from a number of sources, so read on for all the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since these servers are virtual servers running under &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;, I first consulted the VMware Knowledge Base and turned up this article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/support/kb/enduser/std_adp.php?p_sid=Nuh3rAXh&amp;amp;p_lva=&amp;amp;p_faqid=1420&amp;amp;p_created=1093994398&amp;amp;p_sp=cF9zcmNoPTEmcF9ncmlkc29ydD0mcF9yb3dfY250PTc0MyZwX3NlYXJjaF90ZXh0PUxpbnV4IGd1ZXN0IGNsb2NrJnBfc2VhcmNoX3R5cGU9NyZwX3Byb2RfbHZsMT1_YW55fiZwX3Byb2RfbHZsMj1_YW55fiZwX3NvcnRfYnk9ZGZsdCZwX3BhZ2U9MQ**&amp;amp;p_li=&#34;&gt;slow and fast clocks for Linux guest VMs&lt;/a&gt;. Based on that information, I added a few extra commands to the grub configuration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;noapic nosmp nolapic clock=pit
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I found a number of forum postings in various sites (too many to list or link here) that referenced problems with NTP and ACPI. So, based on that information, I further edited the grub configuration to look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;noapic nosmp nolapic clock=pit acpi=no
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, based on information regarding NTP itself and the NTP configuration parameters, I added the &amp;ldquo;burst iburst&amp;rdquo; parameters to the server lines in my &lt;code&gt;ntp.conf&lt;/code&gt; file, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;server W.X.Y.Z burst iburst
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This helped, as at least now NTP would synchronize against something other than the local clock (which was more than it had done previously). For some reason, though, the &lt;code&gt;/var/log/messages&lt;/code&gt; log file was filling up with messages about synchronizing against the local clock, then synchronizing against the server, then against the local clock, etc. (You get the picture.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that I was synchronizing against a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windowsserver2003/default.mspx&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2003&lt;/a&gt;-based computer, I thought perhaps that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s NTP implementation was simply broken. (This certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the first time.) So I configured &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openntpd.org/&#34;&gt;OpenNTPd&lt;/a&gt; on an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org/&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; server (running OpenBSD 3.8) and re-configured the CentOS server to synchronize against the OpenBSD NTP server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;OpenNTPd is ridiculously simple to configure and operate, and _just works._&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The repetitive synchronization messages still appeared, but were appearing with far less frequency. And the time still isn&amp;rsquo;t synchronized to the level I would like, but it does stay within a minute or so of the rest of the network (well within the 5 minute gap required in order for Kerberos authentication to work).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it&amp;rsquo;s still not working as cleanly as the older Red Hat Linux 9.0-based servers, but it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; working. Given that I&amp;rsquo;m still running these servers under an old version of VMware (which, technically, doesn&amp;rsquo;t support Linux 2.6 kernels) I may try upgrading to a new version of VMware to see if that helps at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>NTPd on CentOS 4.2</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/19/ntpd-on-centos-42/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2005 16:08:20 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/19/ntpd-on-centos-42/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back, I started working with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.centos.org/&#34;&gt;CentOS&lt;/a&gt; (version 4.1 at the time, see my &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/08/08/brief-impressions-of-centos-41/&#34;&gt;impressions&lt;/a&gt; here) as a candidate replacement for the Red Hat Linux 9.0-based servers still in service on the network. Although I was (and still am) very comfortable with Red Hat Linux 9.0, it&amp;rsquo;s getting a bit long in the tooth and I wanted to update the servers to a more modern software base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem is, I kept running into &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/08/16/strange-ntpd-problem-on-centos-41/&#34;&gt;issues with time synchronization&lt;/a&gt; on the CentOS server. This time synchronization issue did &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; appear on the Red Hat Linux servers. I tried to resolve the issue, but never did find the solution. Instead, I just used ntpdate in a cron job. That seemed to work well enough, but I really wanted it to work PROPERLY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I started working with CentOS 4.2 earlier this week, hoping that whatever had plagued me with the previous version wouldn&amp;rsquo;t afflict me this time. Unfortunately, the exact same problem has cropped up again, and I am at a loss trying to figure out why it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. The output from &lt;code&gt;ntpq -p&lt;/code&gt; indicates that communication is occurring with the desired time servers, but the NTP daemon still keeps choosing to synchronize with the local clock. SELinux is disabled, so it can&amp;rsquo;t be interfering with NTP (I think that was the problem with the earlier CentOS 4.1 installation), &lt;code&gt;iptables&lt;/code&gt; is not running (so it can&amp;rsquo;t be a firewall issue), file permissions and ownership look OK&amp;mdash;what could I be missing? If anyone has any ideas, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Application-Specific VPNs</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/13/application-specific-vpns/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2005 11:18:37 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/13/application-specific-vpns/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I coined the term &amp;ldquo;application specific VPNs&amp;rdquo; as I began exploring the many uses of tools such as SSH (the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openssh.org/&#34;&gt;OpenSSH&lt;/a&gt; implementation, in particular) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://stunnel.mirt.net/index.html&#34;&gt;Stunnel&lt;/a&gt; (the open source &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Sockets_Layer&#34;&gt;SSL&lt;/a&gt; wrapper). An &amp;ldquo;application specific VPN&amp;rdquo; is a technique for employing encrypted communication with a particular remote application that does not affect the operation of other applications (local or remote) on the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, most VPNs employ technology such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PPTP&#34;&gt;PPTP&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ipsec&#34;&gt;IPSec&lt;/a&gt;. These protocols usually affect &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; traffic originating from that system (unless we use split tunneling). With an application specific VPN, only particular types of traffic are affected, and these particular types of traffic are wrapped in an encrypted SSH or SSL tunnel using either OpenSSH or Stunnel, respectively. Other types of traffic are unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this may seem old hat to long-time Linux, Unix, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; users, this is a relatively new concept to other platforms. Being a (fairly) new convert to Mac OS X myself, I found myself enjoying the tremendous flexibility offered by application specific VPNs. However, this functionality is certainly not limited to these platforms, and it is possible for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; users to utilize this functionality as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Some Examples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of how you can use application specific VPNs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.citrix.com/English/ps2/products/product.asp?contentID=186&amp;amp;ntref=PROHOME_Main&#34;&gt;Citrix Presentation Server&lt;/a&gt;: Users can wrap Citrix ICA traffic in SSL using Stunnel; this avoids the need to pay for commercial solutions (although, quite honestly, the commercial solutions are typically easier to deploy and manage).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;E-Mail: Lots of people talk about securing e-mail, but not usually in the context of securing client-to-server traffic. With Stunnel, you can add SSL support for IMAP, POP, and/or SMTP even if the server doesn&amp;rsquo;t support SSL natively. In fact, you can add Stunnel to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/default.mspx&#34;&gt;Microsoft Exchange&lt;/a&gt; to help bolster that product&amp;rsquo;s built-in support for SSL (such as using SMTPS instead of STARTTLS for encrypting SMTP traffic).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remote Desktop: This is a great technique for sysadmins. Need to use Remote Desktop to manage a Windows-based server remotely, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to run into security problems? Use Stunnel or OpenSSH to encrypt the RDP traffic. Stunnel, in my opinion, is particularly good here, since it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly easy to use the Windows port of Stunnel to establish an SSL listener on an arbitrary high port for this very purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Using Stunnel for SSL-based Application Specific VPNs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Windows, there is no graphical user interface (GUI) for configuring Stunnel; all configuration must be done with the &lt;code&gt;stunnel.conf&lt;/code&gt; configuration file. A sample &lt;code&gt;stunnel.conf&lt;/code&gt; file is found below; this file listens on TCP port 1494 and forwards traffic to TCP port 3389 on the same system. (Note that this would be a sample &lt;code&gt;stunnel.conf&lt;/code&gt; file for a server-side configuration.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;CApath = c:\windows\system32\stunnel  
cert = c:\windows\system32\stunnel\stunnel.pem  
client = no  
service = SSLTunnel  
[rdp]  
accept = 1494  
connect = 3389
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Stunnel has been configured, running &lt;code&gt;stunnel --install&lt;/code&gt; will install it as a system service; this service can then be stopped and started through the Services MMC console just like any other background service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is only half the work; you&amp;rsquo;ll also need an equivalent Stunnel configuration on the client side, since the Microsoft RDP client (the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=80111f21-d48d-426e-96c2-08aa2bd23a49&amp;amp;DisplayLang=en&#34;&gt;Windows version&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/mac/otherproducts/otherproducts.aspx?pid=remotedesktopclient&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; version) does not support SSL. Also, note that the SSL certificate used by Stunnel needs to be in PEM format (which is a nice lead-in to my article discussing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/12/02/certificate-conversion-using-openssl/&#34;&gt;conversion of certificates&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mac OS X, there is a graphical utility for managing Stunnel called SSL Enabler. (Note that I was not able to find a home page for this utility; downloads can be found at various sites.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Linux, the configuration again involves editing the &lt;code&gt;stunnel.conf&lt;/code&gt; file and launching stunnel (either in the foreground or as a daemon). I&amp;rsquo;m not aware of any GUI utilities for configuring Stunnel on Linux, but that certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean they don&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Using SSH for Application Specific VPNs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with Stunnel, it&amp;rsquo;s also possible to use SSH to create application specific VPNs. Mac OS X comes with OpenSSH, as do most distributions of Linux and various flavors of BSD. Windows users can also find various ports of OpenSSH and utilities such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/&#34;&gt;PuTTY&lt;/a&gt; that make it possible to use SSH for application specific VPNs as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mac OS X, the following command in Terminal will create an application specific VPN to encrypt IMAP traffic to a remote server:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh -L 1143:imapserver.domain.com:143 -N -f user@sshserver.domain.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This same technique could be used to encrypt WebDAV traffic to a remote web server, other types of mail traffic (POP3 or SMTP, for example), RDP (for Remote Desktop), etc. Note that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well with HTTP traffic that requires the use of host headers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few graphical utilities on Mac OS X for managing SSH tunnels; these include &lt;a href=&#34;http://projects.tynsoe.org/en/stm/&#34;&gt;SSH Tunnel Manager&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leapingbytes.com/almostvpn&#34;&gt;AlmostVPN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not being a regular day-to-day Linux user (not on the desktop, at least), I don&amp;rsquo;t know of any SSH tunnel management applications, but I would be very surprised if they didn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Creating Site-to-Site Application Specific VPNs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the examples so far have been using SSH and/or Stunnel to connect endpoints (i.e., a single laptop or desktop computer) to a remote resource via an application specific VPN. However, it&amp;rsquo;s also easily possible to create application specific site-to-site VPNs, whose purpose is to secure only a particular type of traffic between two locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this example. CompanyA wants to send e-mail to CompanyB, but wants that e-mail to be secure. If both mail servers support TLS, then the organizations could use TLS to secure the SMTP traffic. If not, then the companies can use Stunnel to establish an SSL connection between two systems. HostA at CompanyA can use Stunnel as a client side application to listen for unencrypted connections and pass them as encrypted connections to HostB at CompanyB. HostB at CompanyB is using Stunnel to listen for encrypted connections and passes them unencrypted to the mail server at CompanyB. With a simple configuration, the mail servers at both companies can be configured to pass mail connections for other company through the Stunnel connection. With no additional cost and very little configuration, all e-mail traffic between the two organizations has now been secured. All this without the complexity of a typical B-to-B VPN and the associated access controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, documents on &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/downloads/ptd-asvpn-ssh.doc&#34;&gt;application specific VPNs with SSH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/downloads/ptd-asvpn-stunnel.doc&#34;&gt;application specific VPNs with Stunnel&lt;/a&gt; are available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Using .Mac iDisk with a WatchGuard Firebox</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/12/using-mac-idisk-with-a-watchguard-firebox/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2005 00:37:38 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/12/using-mac-idisk-with-a-watchguard-firebox/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the strengths of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.watchguard.com/&#34;&gt;WatchGuard&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.watchguard.com/products/appliances.asp&#34;&gt;Firebox&lt;/a&gt; series of firewalls is the inclusion of application-layer proxies for protocols such as SMTP, FTP, and HTTP. Whereas ordinary packet filtering firewalls and stateful inspection firewalls only control traffic based on IP address or TCP/UDP port number, application-layer proxies like those included in the Firebox look deeper into the packet to make decisions on information such as URL or MIME content type (for an HTTP proxy, for example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this advantage also becomes a disadvantage as many application-layer proxies may not understand or be compatible with protocol-specific extensions. In this particular case, it&amp;rsquo;s the iDisk service provided by Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mac.com/&#34;&gt;.Mac&lt;/a&gt; subscription service. The iDisk service uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.webdav.org/&#34;&gt;WebDAV&lt;/a&gt;, an extension of the HTTP/1.1 protocol specification. It appears that, in general, most WebDAV services operate properly through the Fireboxs HTTP proxy (although some issues with Microsoft Exchange&amp;rsquo;s Outlook Web Access were reported with earlier versions of the WatchGuard Firebox System software).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iDisk service, though, apparently uses some non-RFC-compliant headers (note that this was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; confirmed with a packet capture). As a result, the Proxied-HTTP service (which employs, as the name suggests, an application-layer HTTP proxy) prevents these headers from being passed and therefore prevents iDisk from working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make iDisk work from behind a WatchGuard Firebox firewall, one of several steps must be taken:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the Filtered-HTTP service, which does not employ an application-layer HTTP proxy and therefore would not interfere with iDisk or other WebDAV-based applications or services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Modify the default properties of the Proxied-HTTP service to allow unknown headers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the Proxied-HTTP service also provides for content filtering and reporting, it is generally preferred to use the HTTP proxy instead of an ordinary HTTP packet filter. The first option is therefore not the ideal solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, the behavior of the Proxied-HTTP service is somewhat configurable. In order to make iDisk work with the HTTP proxy, the &amp;ldquo;Remove unknown headers&amp;rdquo; option must be unchecked in the configuration for the HTTP proxy. By unchecking the &amp;ldquo;Remove unknown headers&amp;rdquo; option, the Firebox will allow non-RFC-compliant HTTP headers to pass through the firewall, and iDisk will work correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>HTTP Proxies and Command-Line Utilities</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/01/http-proxies-and-command-line-utilities/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 20:14:12 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/01/http-proxies-and-command-line-utilities/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A few weeks ago, I locked down outbound HTTP traffic from my network. All outbound HTTP traffic must now pass through a caching HTTP proxy. (The proxy also performs some content filtering so that the kids don&amp;rsquo;t access stuff they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my recent experiments with &lt;a href=&#34;http://kubuntu.org/&#34;&gt;Kubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, I needed to download some small files using wget, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t because of the proxy. As it turns out, there is a really simple fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simply set an environment variable called http_proxy to the correct URL of the outbound proxy server, e.g., &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://proxy.company.com:8080&amp;quot;&#34;&gt;http://proxy.company.com:8080&amp;quot;&lt;/a&gt; or whatever. In the bash shell, this can be easily accomplished with this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;export http_proxy=&amp;quot;http://proxy.domain.com:8080&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this environment variable was set properly (I messed up a couple of times trying to set it, getting my bash syntax confused with my tcsh syntax), wget and apt-get worked like a charm. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet tried this with yum on Fedora Core 3, but I anticipate that it will work there as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>ipfw Rules for Bonjour</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/28/ipfw-rules-for-bonjour/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2005 16:11:38 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/28/ipfw-rules-for-bonjour/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I originally published this information on my business website, but thought I&amp;rsquo;d reproduce it here in the event someone needs it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/bonjour/&#34;&gt;Bonjour&lt;/a&gt; (formerly Rendezvous) auto-discovery service is used in a number of Apple-branded products as well as a growing number of third-party applications (for example, my HP Color LaserJet 2550N supports Bonjour). It&amp;rsquo;s used to advertise and discover &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/itunes/&#34;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt; music libraries, and Apple&amp;rsquo;s Airport Admin Utility also uses Bonjour to discover &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/airportextreme/&#34;&gt;Airport Extreme&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/airportexpress/&#34;&gt;Airport Express&lt;/a&gt; wireless base stations for configuration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonjour uses &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.multicastdns.org/&#34;&gt;multicast DNS&lt;/a&gt; (known as mDNS), part of the IETF standard known as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeroconf.org/&#34;&gt;Zeroconf&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that is well and good, but if you are using the built-in firewall you most likely are preventing Bonjour from working correctly. I grew frustrated trying to utilize Bonjour-related services while also keeping my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/powerbook/&#34;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/a&gt; protected against unwanted network traffic. Using a packet sniffer and Brian Hill&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://personalpages.tds.net/~brian_hill/brickhouse.html&#34;&gt;Brickhouse&lt;/a&gt; application, I observed Bonjour traffic and created a set of ipfw rules that can be used to allow this traffic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multicast DNS operates over UDP (IP protocol 17) with a destination port 5353 and a source port above 1024. The destination address is, of course, a multicast address (in the 224.0.0.0 range). Responses to mDNS multicasts originate from UDP port 5353, but are bound for a random high port above 1024. Simply defining a rule that allows traffic to and from UDP port 5353 wont work, because while outbound traffic will be correctly matched the responses to those outbound requests wont be matched and will be dropped (assuming the default action is to deny traffic). So, a sample rule to be added to ipfw might look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;add 2008 allow udp from 10.1.1.0/24 5353 to any 1024-65535 in via en0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This should be entered all on a single line.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This rule allows traffic from the source network 10.1.1.0 (the &amp;ldquo;/24&amp;rdquo; indicating a 24-bit mask, i.e., a subnet mask of 255.255.255.0) from UDP source port 5353 to any port above 1024 on any destination address inbound via the en0 interface. The en0 interface is typically the built-in Ethernet interface on most &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;-based systems. (Likewise, en1 is typically the built-in AirPort/AirPort Extreme wireless interface.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are tightly restricting outbound traffic as well, you&amp;rsquo;ll need a matching outbound rule (of course).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My own experience has shown that adding this rule to my ipfw ruleset has allowed Bonjour to work as expected without sacrificing the security of my system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Cisco PIX VPN and Active Directory Integration</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/22/cisco-pix-vpn-and-active-directory-integration/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2005 19:01:54 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/22/cisco-pix-vpn-and-active-directory-integration/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;Rather than publishing this information in PDF form on my business website, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try something new and post it here as a blog entry. So, here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This information assumes that you have some experience with the Cisco PIX firewall (i.e., you know how to enter configuration commands and have a basic idea of what the configuration commands actually do) as well as some experience with Windows and Active Directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that information in hand, let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Configuring the Cisco PIX&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we&amp;rsquo;ll need to setup the PIX firewall. Use the commands below to configure the PIX for PPTP-based VPN connections that will authenticate against an Active Directory back-end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ip local pool vpn-pool 10.10.10.1-10.10.10.254  
aaa-server vpn-auth inside host 10.10.10.5 secretkey  
aaa-server vpn-auth inside host 10.10.10.6 secretkey  
aaa-server vpn-auth protocol radius  
vpdn group vpn-pptp-group accept dialin pptp  
vpdn group vpn-pptp-group ppp authentication mschap  
vpdn group vpn-pptp-group ppp encryption mppe 128 required  
vpdn group vpn-pptp-group client configuration \  
address local vpn-pool  
vpdn group vpn-pptp-group client configuration \  
dns 10.10.10.5 10.10.10.6  
vpdn group vpn-pptp-group client configuration \  
wins 10.10.10.6 10.10.10.5  
vpdn group vpn-pptp-group client authentication aaa vpn-auth  
vpdn enable outside  
sysopt connect permit-pptp  
access-list acl-nat0 permit ip 10.10.1.0 255.255.255.0 \  
10.10.10.0 255.255.255.0  
nat (inside) 0 access-list acl-nat0
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note that I have placed a backslash to indicate text that is wrapped onto two lines here but should be entered all on a single line in the PIX configuration.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this configuration, replace the IP addresses on lines 2 and 3 (the &lt;code&gt;aaa-server vpn-auth&lt;/code&gt; commands) with the IP addresses of the servers running Internet Authentication Service (IAS) on Windows. See the next section for more information on configuring IAS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On those same lines, replace the text &lt;code&gt;secretkey&lt;/code&gt; with the RADIUS shared secret that will be used when configuring the RADIUS/IAS server in the next section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Likewise, replace the IP addresses on lines 9 and 10 (the &lt;code&gt;vdpn group vpn-pptp-group client configuration&lt;/code&gt; lines that pass out the DNS and WINS servers to VPN clients) with the IP addresses of your DNS and WINS servers, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should do it. Save the configuration to the PIX and then move on to configuring IAS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Configuring Internet Authentication Service&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before doing anything else, create a new global security group in Active Directory. Call it something like &amp;ldquo;VPN Users&amp;rdquo; or similar. We&amp;rsquo;ll use this group later as an additional security check in validating VPN connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, install IAS using the Add/Remove Programs icon in Control Panel. Once it has been installed, launch it from the Administrative Tools folder on the Start Menu and we&amp;rsquo;ll proceed with configuring it for authenticating VPN connections to the PIX firewall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we need to grant IAS permission to read dial-in properties from user accounts in Active Directory. To do this, right-click on the &amp;ldquo;Internet Authentication Service (Local)&amp;rdquo; and select &amp;ldquo;Register Server in Active Directory&amp;rdquo;. Select Yes (or OK) if prompted to confirm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that done, we can now configure the PIX firewall as a RADIUS client. Right-click on RADIUS Clients and select New RADIUS Client. In the wizard, specify the IP address (or DNS name) of the PIX firewall&amp;rsquo;s internal IP address and the shared secret. Note that this shared secret is the same secret key specified in the PIX configuration above. RADIUS clients use this to authenticate to RADIUS servers, so make it a reasonably strong password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now create a remote access policy. Right-click on Remote Access Policies and select New Remote Access Policy. In the wizard, specify a name, select to create a custom policy, and then add the following conditions to the policy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NAS-IP-Address: This will be the IP address of the PIX firewall&amp;rsquo;s internal interface. This helps to ensure that this policy only applies to VPN requests from this firewall and not from any other RADIUS client.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows-Groups: This should be the security group created earlier. Any user that should be allowed to authenticate on a VPN connection will need to be a member of this group.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the policy should be very straightforward. Make this policy the first policy (using the Move Up/Move Down commands in the IAS console), add a user to the group created earlier, and then test your connection. Remote systems attempting to connect via PPTP should now be able to authenticate the VPN connection using their Active Directory usernames and passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although this was written from the perspective of authenticating PPTP connections, the process should be very similar for IPSec VPN clients as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>OpenBSD pcn0 Driver Issue Resolved</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/04/openbsd-pcn0-driver-issue-resolved/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2005 08:48:20 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/04/openbsd-pcn0-driver-issue-resolved/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, sort of resolved. I was never able to make the &lt;code&gt;pcn&lt;/code&gt; driver (from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org/&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; 3.8) actually work under &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;, but I did find information on how to disable the &lt;code&gt;pcn&lt;/code&gt; driver and revert to the older &lt;code&gt;le&lt;/code&gt; driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://archives.neohapsis.com/archives/openbsd/2005-08/1314.html&#34;&gt;archived Neohapsis discussion&lt;/a&gt;, followed by a quick e-mail exchange with the author of the thread (who, thankfully, was very responsive and very helpful) led me to the solution. Some of it I had to improvise on the fly, but here&amp;rsquo;s the overall process:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boot from the OpenBSD 3.8 boot CD image (I pointed the virtual CD-ROM drive in the VM directly to the corresponding ISO image).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the OpenBSD &amp;ldquo;boot&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo; prompt, type &amp;ldquo;-c&amp;rdquo; and press Enter. This takes you into User Kernel Config, or UKC.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the UKC prompt, type &amp;ldquo;disable pcn&amp;rdquo; to disable the &lt;code&gt;pcn&lt;/code&gt; driver.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Type &amp;ldquo;quit&amp;rdquo; at the next UKC prompt to exit the kernel config and proceed with the boot process. If you watch the boot process, you will see OpenBSD load the &lt;code&gt;le&lt;/code&gt; driver and identify the virtual NIC as &lt;code&gt;le1&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s all well and good, but how do you make the changes stick between reboots? Here&amp;rsquo;s how.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve gotten OpenBSD fully installed and are rebooting for the first time after installation, follow the steps above to use the &lt;code&gt;le&lt;/code&gt; driver for the next reboot.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the &amp;ldquo;config -e -o nbsd bsd&amp;rdquo; command (see the relevant &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org/cgi-bin/man.cgi?query=config&amp;amp;apropos=0&amp;amp;sektion=0&amp;amp;manpath=OpenBSD+3.8&amp;amp;arch=i386&amp;amp;format=html&#34;&gt;man page&lt;/a&gt; for details) to modify the kernel again, only this time saving the changes to the file named &amp;ldquo;nbsd&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon the next reboot after using the config command to create a new kernel file, specify the name of that new kernel file (&amp;ldquo;nbsd&amp;rdquo; in our example here) at the OpenBSD &amp;ldquo;boot&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo; prompt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assuming that everything works OK (it did for me), rename the original kernel to &amp;ldquo;bsd.original&amp;rdquo; and rename your new kernel to just &amp;ldquo;bsd&amp;rdquo;. Then, upon the next reboot, the &lt;code&gt;pcn&lt;/code&gt; driver should be disabled and everything should work just fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this process, I now have two OpenBSD 3.8 VMs running and haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced any issues. Now, on to installing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clamav.net/&#34;&gt;ClamAV&lt;/a&gt; on OpenBSD&amp;hellip;.&lt;em&gt;(more details soon)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;code&gt;pcn0&lt;/code&gt; network driver from OpenBSD 3.9 works perfectly under VMware (at least, on ESX Server). I have posted more information &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2006/05/18/openbsd-39-on-esx-server/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Follow Up on Access-Based Enumeration</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/11/follow-up-on-access-based-enumeration/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2005 21:53:54 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/11/follow-up-on-access-based-enumeration/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As a follow-up to &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/07/08/access-based-enumeration/&#34;&gt;this posting&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windowsserver2003/techinfo/overview/abe.mspx&#34;&gt;access-based enumeration&lt;/a&gt;, I wanted to post information from some testing I performed earlier this week. I installed access-based enumeration (ABE) on a server running &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windowsserver2003/default.mspx&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2003&lt;/a&gt; SP1 (the only version of Windows on which it is supported). It does what it advertises; when a non-administrative user connects to a shared folder on which ABE is enabled, they see only those folders to which he or she has permission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some limitations. Administrative users are not affected in any way. ABE only works for network access; users accessing the filesystem locally are not affected. This makes ABE unsuitable for use on terminal servers. Additionally, ABE is enabled or disabled on a share-by-share basis, and while it is possible to turn ABE on or off for all shares at a time there is no provision for setting ABE on by default for new shares. Finally, ABE can negatively impact performance, especially for shared folders with large numbers of files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m kind of split on this one. On the one hand, it&amp;rsquo;s really good functionality that will dramatically change the way system administrators approach Windows-based file servers. On the other hand, the potential performance drawbacks of ABE are concerning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are running file servers on Windows Server 2003 with Service Pack 1 installed, you owe it to yourself to at least evaluate ABE. You may find that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for your network, but then again you may find that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to go on without the added functionality that ABE brings to the table.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>VPN Integration Done</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/27/vpn-integration-done/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2005 00:23:45 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/27/vpn-integration-done/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;That was easier than I expected. I managed to get my hardware firewall to authenticate VPN connections against Active Directory via &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RADIUS&#34;&gt;RADIUS&lt;/a&gt; (using Internet Authentication Service, or IAS) without a great deal of effort. In fact, it was almost easy. If I ever get caught up on documentation, I&amp;rsquo;ll post some details on how to do it on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mercurionsystems.com/index.html&#34;&gt;Mercurion Systems&lt;/a&gt; web site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linux-AD Integration Wrap-Up</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/22/linux-ad-integration-wrap-up/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2005 00:19:08 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/22/linux-ad-integration-wrap-up/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, my Linux-AD integration task is pretty much complete. I have three Linux servers authenticating via &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/kerberos/www&#34;&gt;Kerberos&lt;/a&gt; to Active Directory, and using LDAP for name/group resolution. Only one Linux server remains; I need to do some research on how &lt;a href=&#34;http://asg.web.cmu.edu/sasl/&#34;&gt;SASL&lt;/a&gt; with interact with PAM before I can switch over that particular server. My &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; server I&amp;rsquo;m going to leave alone for now; perhaps later I&amp;rsquo;ll get it integrated as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to see what is involved in using RADIUS to authenticate VPN tunnels on my hardware firewall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Bonjour (The Technology, Not the Greeting)</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/11/bonjour-the-technology-not-the-greeting/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2005 23:39:46 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/11/bonjour-the-technology-not-the-greeting/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the RSS feeds from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macosxhints.com&#34;&gt;Mac OS X Hints&lt;/a&gt; today pointed me to a website on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dns-sd.org/&#34;&gt;DNS Service Discovery (DNS-SD)&lt;/a&gt;. DNS-SD is part of the magic behind &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/bonjour/&#34;&gt;Bonjour&lt;/a&gt; (formerly named Rendezvous), the way in which &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; is able to automatically locate services across the network. Bonjour is used, for example, in locating an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/airportextreme/&#34;&gt;Airport Extreme&lt;/a&gt; base station, or used by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org&#34;&gt;Camino&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/features/safari/&#34;&gt;Safari&lt;/a&gt; to find web servers on your network. Personally, I like Bonjour, and it&amp;rsquo;s good to see that it is finally being extended beyond single-segment implementations. And, with &lt;a href=&#34;http://a1408.g.akamai.net/7/1408/9955/20050505/akamai.info.apple.com/Bonjour/061-1768.20050505.BJWdw/BonjourSetup.exe&#34;&gt;Bonjour for Windows&lt;/a&gt; available from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s starting to look like a viable cross-platform solution for finding and connecting to network services automatically.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Access-Based Enumeration</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/08/access-based-enumeration/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2005 23:29:04 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/08/access-based-enumeration/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windowsserver2003/&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2003&lt;/a&gt; has finally caught up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.novell.com/netware/&#34;&gt;Novell NetWare&lt;/a&gt; in one key area, and that is in the enumeration of files and folders. With &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=04A563D9-78D9-4342-A485-B030AC442084&amp;amp;displaylang=en&#34;&gt;access-based enumeration&lt;/a&gt;, Windows Server 2003 now will display only those files and folders to which the user has permission. If no permission is given, the file or folder is not displayed. This is, in my opinion, a &lt;em&gt;major&lt;/em&gt; improvement in Windows&amp;rsquo; security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to give this functionality a swing on my own servers within the next few days. I&amp;rsquo;ll post additional details here after my tests.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Virtualization</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/26/virtualization/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2005 16:01:32 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/26/virtualization/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtualization/&#34;&gt;virtualization&lt;/a&gt;. I love the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt; products (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/desktop/ws_features.html&#34;&gt;VMware Workstation&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/server/gsx_features.html&#34;&gt;GSX Server&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/products/server/esx_features.html&#34;&gt;ESX Server&lt;/a&gt;) and, as I have mentioned in previous posts, use Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/mac/products/virtualpc/virtualpc.aspx&#34;&gt;Virtual PC&lt;/a&gt; product currently (but only because VMware doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a Mac version of VMware Workstation). I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to hardware-based virtualization technologies such as AMD&amp;rsquo;s Pacifica (discussed briefly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1780606,00.asp&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1820551,00.asp&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) and Intel&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intel.com/technology/computing/vptech/&#34;&gt;Vanderpool&lt;/a&gt; technology. I&amp;rsquo;m very much hoping that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; will take the plunge and build in virtualization support in Mac OS X 10.5, aka &amp;ldquo;Leopard&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Virtualization is more than just running multiple operating systems on a single computer, though. Virtualization occurs in networking through the use of virtual LANs (VLANs) and virtual private networks (VPNs); both of these technologies are core technologies in today&amp;rsquo;s flexible networks. Virtualization occurs in storage area networks (SANs) as virtual disks and virtual SANs (VSANs). Technologies such as load balancing via virtual servers (recently read an interesting &lt;a href=&#34;http://software.newsforge.com/article.pl?sid=05/05/27/0612243&#34;&gt;article on Linux virtual servers&lt;/a&gt;) also employ a form of virtualization. Even mundane technologies such as network address translation (NAT) can be considered forms of virtualization, since they abstract a server&amp;rsquo;s public IP address from its private (actual) IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As IT professionals, it behooves us to embrace new technologies like virtualization, in all its forms. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t already taken the time to get used to these kinds of products and technologies, now might be a good time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Some Cool Networking Stuff</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/17/some-cool-networking-stuff/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2005 00:19:21 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/17/some-cool-networking-stuff/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I setup some cool networking stuff today with some &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hp.com/&#34;&gt;HP&lt;/a&gt; ProCurve switches. A customer of mine was converting from a T-1 based WAN to an Ethernet MAN. The carrier brought in a separate Ethernet drop for each location, and I configured a separate port-based VLAN for each drop and then set up routing between them. All in all, it took about an hour to convert all the locations from the old WAN to the new MAN, and 50 minutes of that was spent driving from location to location (everything is in the same city).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it&amp;rsquo;s nothing unusual (I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are those of you out there that do this stuff everyday), but I was particularly pleased at how smoothly we managed to make the conversion for all 12 locations. Plus, I&amp;rsquo;d done this before many times with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cisco.com/&#34;&gt;Cisco&lt;/a&gt; equipment, but this was only the second time using HP equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll probably do a write-up of this on my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mercurionsystems.com/&#34;&gt;company web site&lt;/a&gt;. If you are interested in more details, look there soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
