<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/tags/music/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-11-22 12:57:33 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Another Take on Life(song)</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/22/another-take-on-lifesong/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2005 12:57:33 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/22/another-take-on-lifesong/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/&#34;&gt;earlier posting&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;em&gt;Lifesong&lt;/em&gt;, the second CD by the Christian group &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castingcrowns.org/home.php&#34;&gt;Casting Crowns&lt;/a&gt;, I spoke primarily about their musical style and their sound. At the time, I was so wrapped up in how the music sounded in comparison with their debut album that I was disappointed in this latest effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued listening to the CD, concentrating mostly on the tracks that I really enjoyed&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Lifesong&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Praise You in This Storm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Set Me Free&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Father, Spirit, Jesus&amp;rdquo;. As I listened&amp;mdash;truly listened&amp;mdash;to the words of these songs, and then took the time to listen to the other songs on the album as well, I realized that I was guilty of the very things that Casting Crowns sings about in these songs. And my first review was the perfect indicator of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many people practice Christianity on the surface. Sure, they go to church. They may even teach Sunday School, or lead a Bible study group. But do they really serve the Lord? Is their service&amp;mdash;my service&amp;mdash;just &amp;ldquo;empty hands held high&amp;rdquo;? How often do we high our true feelings from others, even our fellow Christians, becoming &amp;ldquo;happy plastic people under shiny plastic steeples&amp;rdquo;? Can we see past that young unwed mother&amp;rsquo;s sin, see &amp;ldquo;past her scarlet letter&amp;rdquo; and actually get to know her?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This entry isn&amp;rsquo;t just about a CD, though; that&amp;rsquo;s why I titled this post &amp;ldquo;Another Take on Life(song)&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about &lt;em&gt;Lifesong&lt;/em&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s about &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s time for us&amp;mdash;for me&amp;mdash;to move past superficial Christianity and into true service for the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean full-time ministry, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean just going to church. It means serving the Lord with all that we are and in all that we do (and my use of the term &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; here includes myself). It means living a life that &amp;ldquo;brings a smile&amp;rdquo; to the Lord, where we take to heart Jesus&amp;rsquo; teachings and actually apply them in all areas of life, not just the areas that are convenient or comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means letting our life(song) sing to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Lifesong by Casting Crowns</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2005 00:06:08 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I received a copy of the new album by Casting Crowns today, &lt;em&gt;Lifesong&lt;/em&gt;. There are a couple of really good tracks, like the title track &amp;ldquo;Lifesong,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Father, Spirit, Jesus&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Set Me Free.&amp;rdquo; Most of the songs, though, are a very different style than Casting Crowns&amp;rsquo; debut album. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit disappointed. After so thoroughly enjoying their first CD, I was really looking forward to their next album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that the CD is bad. It just wasn&amp;rsquo;t what I had expected. Songs from their first album really moved you, like &amp;ldquo;Voice of Truth&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Who Am I&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;American Dream&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;If We Are The Body&amp;rdquo;. And they did so with a powerful rock sound. These songs, on the other hand, are much softer. The lyrics are good, but the musical style is not what I was hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again, a few of the tracks from the original album didn&amp;rsquo;t really strike me the first time I heard them, but as I listened to them again I began to enjoy them more. Perhaps the same will happen here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
