<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/tags/oss/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-12-23 14:50:45 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>CentOS NTPd Problem (Mostly) Resolved</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/23/centos-ntpd-problem-mostly-resolved/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2005 14:50:45 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/23/centos-ntpd-problem-mostly-resolved/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The NTPd problem that I &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/08/16/strange-ntpd-problem-on-centos-41/&#34;&gt;wrestled with in CentOS 4.1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/12/19/ntpd-on-centos-42/&#34;&gt;again in CentOS 4.2&lt;/a&gt; has finally been resolved. Mostly. I think. The specific steps I took to resolve the issue came from a number of sources, so read on for all the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since these servers are virtual servers running under &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/&#34;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt;, I first consulted the VMware Knowledge Base and turned up this article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vmware.com/support/kb/enduser/std_adp.php?p_sid=Nuh3rAXh&amp;amp;p_lva=&amp;amp;p_faqid=1420&amp;amp;p_created=1093994398&amp;amp;p_sp=cF9zcmNoPTEmcF9ncmlkc29ydD0mcF9yb3dfY250PTc0MyZwX3NlYXJjaF90ZXh0PUxpbnV4IGd1ZXN0IGNsb2NrJnBfc2VhcmNoX3R5cGU9NyZwX3Byb2RfbHZsMT1_YW55fiZwX3Byb2RfbHZsMj1_YW55fiZwX3NvcnRfYnk9ZGZsdCZwX3BhZ2U9MQ**&amp;amp;p_li=&#34;&gt;slow and fast clocks for Linux guest VMs&lt;/a&gt;. Based on that information, I added a few extra commands to the grub configuration:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;noapic nosmp nolapic clock=pit
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, I found a number of forum postings in various sites (too many to list or link here) that referenced problems with NTP and ACPI. So, based on that information, I further edited the grub configuration to look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;noapic nosmp nolapic clock=pit acpi=no
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, based on information regarding NTP itself and the NTP configuration parameters, I added the &amp;ldquo;burst iburst&amp;rdquo; parameters to the server lines in my &lt;code&gt;ntp.conf&lt;/code&gt; file, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;server W.X.Y.Z burst iburst
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This helped, as at least now NTP would synchronize against something other than the local clock (which was more than it had done previously). For some reason, though, the &lt;code&gt;/var/log/messages&lt;/code&gt; log file was filling up with messages about synchronizing against the local clock, then synchronizing against the server, then against the local clock, etc. (You get the picture.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given that I was synchronizing against a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windowsserver2003/default.mspx&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2003&lt;/a&gt;-based computer, I thought perhaps that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s NTP implementation was simply broken. (This certainly wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the first time.) So I configured &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openntpd.org/&#34;&gt;OpenNTPd&lt;/a&gt; on an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org/&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; server (running OpenBSD 3.8) and re-configured the CentOS server to synchronize against the OpenBSD NTP server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside&gt;OpenNTPd is ridiculously simple to configure and operate, and _just works._&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The repetitive synchronization messages still appeared, but were appearing with far less frequency. And the time still isn&amp;rsquo;t synchronized to the level I would like, but it does stay within a minute or so of the rest of the network (well within the 5 minute gap required in order for Kerberos authentication to work).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it&amp;rsquo;s still not working as cleanly as the older Red Hat Linux 9.0-based servers, but it &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; working. Given that I&amp;rsquo;m still running these servers under an old version of VMware (which, technically, doesn&amp;rsquo;t support Linux 2.6 kernels) I may try upgrading to a new version of VMware to see if that helps at all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Complete Linux-AD Authentication Details</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/22/complete-linux-ad-authentication-details/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2005 11:26:46 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/22/complete-linux-ad-authentication-details/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; These instructions are for Windows 2000 Server and Windows Server 2003 pre-R2. For the R2 release, please see &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2007/01/15/linux-ad-integration-version-4/&#34;&gt;these updated instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several articles posted here that discuss, in general terms, how to authenticate Linux against Active Directory. For example, see this brief article on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/07/13/linux-ad-integration-direction/&#34;&gt;broad direction&lt;/a&gt; of the integration, or this posting on &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/07/18/minor-linux-ad-hiccup-fixed-hopefully/&#34;&gt;using computer accounts&lt;/a&gt; for Linux servers (most how-to documents I&amp;rsquo;ve seen discuss the use of a user account for this purpose).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last week or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having to rebuild one Linux server a number of times in an effort to fix a separate problem (see this article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/08/16/strange-ntpd-problem-on-centos-41/&#34;&gt;NTPd problems with CentOS 4.1&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/12/19/ntpd-on-centos-42/&#34;&gt;recurrence of the problem&lt;/a&gt; with CentOS 4.2). As a result, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to go through the process of configuring this Linux server (and preparing Active Directory) for authentication several times, and I found that I kept having to go back to my scattered and dispersed notes to remember what had to be done. In the hopes of correcting that, I am collecting all the pertinent information I have here in this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Preparing Active Directory (One-Time)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a one-time preparation of Active Directory that is required. In order to authenticate Linux logins against Active Directory, Active Directory&amp;rsquo;s schema must be extended to include Linux-specific attributes such as home directory, UID, GID, and default shell. There are a couple of different ways to do this; I chose to use Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Services for Unix (SFU) to extend the schema. There are two reasons I chose SFU: 1) it&amp;rsquo;s free; and 2) the SFU schema is being included by default in Windows Server 2003 R2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once SFU has been installed and the schema has been extended, then the specific Active Directory accounts that are allowed to authenticate via Linux must be configured with a UID and other UNIX attributes. This is accomplished via the new &amp;ldquo;UNIX Attributes&amp;rdquo; tab on the properties dialog box of a user account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to create an account in Active Directory that will be used to bind to Active Directory for LDAP queries. This account does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; need any special privileges; in fact, making the account a member of Domain Guests and &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a member of Domain Users is perfectly fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all the user accounts have been configured, then we are ready to perform the additional tasks within Active Directory and on the Linux server that will enable the authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Preparing Active Directory (Each Server)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each server that will be authenticating against Active Directory, follow the steps below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a computer account in Active Directory. When creating the computer account, be sure to specify that this account may be used by a pre-Windows 2000-based computer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the following command at a command prompt to configure the new computer account:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ktpass -princ host/fqdn@REALM -mapuser DOMAIN\name$&lt;br /&gt;
-crypto DES-CBC-MD5 -pass password -ptype KRB5_NT_PRINCIPAL&lt;br /&gt;
-out filename&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to substitute the appropriate values for &amp;ldquo;fqdn&amp;rdquo; (the fully-qualified domain name of the computer), &amp;ldquo;REALM&amp;rdquo; (the DNS name of your Active Directory domain in UPPERCASE), &amp;ldquo;DOMAIN&amp;rdquo; (the NetBIOS name of your Active Directory domain), &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo; (the password that will be set for the new computer account), and &amp;ldquo;filename&amp;rdquo; (the keytab that will be generated and must be copied over to the Linux computer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to rebuild the Linux server for whatever reason, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to delete the computer account you created and repeat this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Preparing the Linux Server&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the steps below to configure the Linux server for authentication against Active Directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure that the appropriate Kerberos libraries, OpenLDAP, pam_krb5, and nss_ldap are installed. If they are not installed, install them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be sure that time is being properly synchronized between Active Directory and the Linux server in question. Kerberos requires time synchronization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the &lt;code&gt;krb5.conf&lt;/code&gt; file to look something like this, substituting your actual host names and domain names where appropriate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[logging]&lt;br /&gt;
 default = FILE:/var/log/krb5libs.log&lt;br /&gt;
 kdc = FILE:/var/log/krb5kdc.log&lt;br /&gt;
 admin_server = FILE:/var/log/kadmind.log&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[libdefaults]&lt;br /&gt;
 default_realm = EXAMPLE.COM&lt;br /&gt;
 dns_lookup_realm = true&lt;br /&gt;
 dns_lookup_kdc = true&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[realms]&lt;br /&gt;
 EXAMPLE.COM = {&lt;br /&gt;
  kdc = host.example.com:88&lt;br /&gt;
  admin_server = host.example.com:749&lt;br /&gt;
  default_domain = example.com&lt;br /&gt;
 }&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[domain_realm]&lt;br /&gt;
 .example.com = EXAMPLE.COM&lt;br /&gt;
 example.com = EXAMPLE.COM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[kdc]&lt;br /&gt;
 profile = /var/kerberos/krb5kdc/kdc.conf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[appdefaults]&lt;br /&gt;
 pam = {&lt;br /&gt;
   debug = false&lt;br /&gt;
   ticket_lifetime = 36000&lt;br /&gt;
   renew_lifetime = 36000&lt;br /&gt;
   forwardable = true&lt;br /&gt;
   krb4_convert = false&lt;br /&gt;
 }&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the &lt;code&gt;/etc/ldap.conf&lt;/code&gt; file to look something like this, substituting the appropriate host names, domain names, account names, and distinguished names (DNs) where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;host 10.10.10.10
base dc=example,dc=com
binddn cn=ldap,cn=Users,dc=example,dc=com
bindpw adldapbindpw
scope sub
ssl no
nss_base_passwd dc=example,dc=com
nss_base_shadow dc=example,dc=com
nss_base_group dc=example,dc=com
nss_map_objectclass posixAccount user
nss_map_objectclass shadowAccount user
nss_map_objectclass posixGroup group
nss_map_attribute uid sAMAccountName
nss_map_attribute uidNumber msSFU30UidNumber
nss_map_attribute gidNumber msSFU30GidNumber
nss_map_attribute loginShell msSFU30LoginShell
nss_map_attribute gecos name
nss_map_attribute userPassword msSFU30Password
nss_map_attribute homeDirectory msSFU30HomeDirectory
nss_map_attribute uniqueMember msSFU30PosixMember
nss_map_attribute cn cn&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Securely copy the file created using the &lt;code&gt;ktpass.exe&lt;/code&gt; utility above to the Linux server in question, placing it in the &lt;code&gt;/etc&lt;/code&gt; directory as &lt;code&gt;krb5.keytab&lt;/code&gt;. (SFTP or SCP are excellent candidates for this.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Configure PAM (this varies according to Linux distributions) to use pam_krb5 for authentication. Many modern distributions use a stacking mechanism whereby one file can be modified and those changes will applied to all the various PAM-aware services. For example, in Red Hat-based distributions, the system-auth file is referenced by most other PAM-aware services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the &lt;code&gt;/etc/nsswitch.conf&lt;/code&gt; file to include &amp;ldquo;ldap&amp;rdquo; as a lookup source for passwd, shadow, and groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should be it. Once you do that, you should be able to use &lt;code&gt;kinit&lt;/code&gt; from a Linux shell prompt (for example, &lt;code&gt;kinit aduser&lt;/code&gt;) and generate a valid Kerberos ticket for the specified Active Directory account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, any PAM-aware service that is configured to use the stacked system file (such as the system-auth configuration on Red Hat-based distributions) will use Active Directory for authentication. Note, however, that unless you also add the &lt;code&gt;pam_mkhomedir.so&lt;/code&gt; module in the PAM configuration, home directories will have to be created manually for any Active Directory account that may log on to that server. (I generally recommend the use of &lt;code&gt;pam_mkhomedir.so&lt;/code&gt; in this situation.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Application-Specific VPNs</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/13/application-specific-vpns/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2005 11:18:37 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/13/application-specific-vpns/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;I coined the term &amp;ldquo;application specific VPNs&amp;rdquo; as I began exploring the many uses of tools such as SSH (the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openssh.org/&#34;&gt;OpenSSH&lt;/a&gt; implementation, in particular) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://stunnel.mirt.net/index.html&#34;&gt;Stunnel&lt;/a&gt; (the open source &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secure_Sockets_Layer&#34;&gt;SSL&lt;/a&gt; wrapper). An &amp;ldquo;application specific VPN&amp;rdquo; is a technique for employing encrypted communication with a particular remote application that does not affect the operation of other applications (local or remote) on the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, most VPNs employ technology such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PPTP&#34;&gt;PPTP&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ipsec&#34;&gt;IPSec&lt;/a&gt;. These protocols usually affect &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; traffic originating from that system (unless we use split tunneling). With an application specific VPN, only particular types of traffic are affected, and these particular types of traffic are wrapped in an encrypted SSH or SSL tunnel using either OpenSSH or Stunnel, respectively. Other types of traffic are unaffected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this may seem old hat to long-time Linux, Unix, or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; users, this is a relatively new concept to other platforms. Being a (fairly) new convert to Mac OS X myself, I found myself enjoying the tremendous flexibility offered by application specific VPNs. However, this functionality is certainly not limited to these platforms, and it is possible for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; users to utilize this functionality as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Some Examples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of how you can use application specific VPNs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.citrix.com/English/ps2/products/product.asp?contentID=186&amp;amp;ntref=PROHOME_Main&#34;&gt;Citrix Presentation Server&lt;/a&gt;: Users can wrap Citrix ICA traffic in SSL using Stunnel; this avoids the need to pay for commercial solutions (although, quite honestly, the commercial solutions are typically easier to deploy and manage).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;E-Mail: Lots of people talk about securing e-mail, but not usually in the context of securing client-to-server traffic. With Stunnel, you can add SSL support for IMAP, POP, and/or SMTP even if the server doesn&amp;rsquo;t support SSL natively. In fact, you can add Stunnel to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/default.mspx&#34;&gt;Microsoft Exchange&lt;/a&gt; to help bolster that product&amp;rsquo;s built-in support for SSL (such as using SMTPS instead of STARTTLS for encrypting SMTP traffic).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remote Desktop: This is a great technique for sysadmins. Need to use Remote Desktop to manage a Windows-based server remotely, but don&amp;rsquo;t want to run into security problems? Use Stunnel or OpenSSH to encrypt the RDP traffic. Stunnel, in my opinion, is particularly good here, since it&amp;rsquo;s incredibly easy to use the Windows port of Stunnel to establish an SSL listener on an arbitrary high port for this very purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Using Stunnel for SSL-based Application Specific VPNs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Windows, there is no graphical user interface (GUI) for configuring Stunnel; all configuration must be done with the &lt;code&gt;stunnel.conf&lt;/code&gt; configuration file. A sample &lt;code&gt;stunnel.conf&lt;/code&gt; file is found below; this file listens on TCP port 1494 and forwards traffic to TCP port 3389 on the same system. (Note that this would be a sample &lt;code&gt;stunnel.conf&lt;/code&gt; file for a server-side configuration.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;CApath = c:\windows\system32\stunnel  
cert = c:\windows\system32\stunnel\stunnel.pem  
client = no  
service = SSLTunnel  
[rdp]  
accept = 1494  
connect = 3389
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once Stunnel has been configured, running &lt;code&gt;stunnel --install&lt;/code&gt; will install it as a system service; this service can then be stopped and started through the Services MMC console just like any other background service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is only half the work; you&amp;rsquo;ll also need an equivalent Stunnel configuration on the client side, since the Microsoft RDP client (the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/downloads/details.aspx?FamilyID=80111f21-d48d-426e-96c2-08aa2bd23a49&amp;amp;DisplayLang=en&#34;&gt;Windows version&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/mac/otherproducts/otherproducts.aspx?pid=remotedesktopclient&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; version) does not support SSL. Also, note that the SSL certificate used by Stunnel needs to be in PEM format (which is a nice lead-in to my article discussing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/12/02/certificate-conversion-using-openssl/&#34;&gt;conversion of certificates&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mac OS X, there is a graphical utility for managing Stunnel called SSL Enabler. (Note that I was not able to find a home page for this utility; downloads can be found at various sites.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Linux, the configuration again involves editing the &lt;code&gt;stunnel.conf&lt;/code&gt; file and launching stunnel (either in the foreground or as a daemon). I&amp;rsquo;m not aware of any GUI utilities for configuring Stunnel on Linux, but that certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean they don&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Using SSH for Application Specific VPNs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with Stunnel, it&amp;rsquo;s also possible to use SSH to create application specific VPNs. Mac OS X comes with OpenSSH, as do most distributions of Linux and various flavors of BSD. Windows users can also find various ports of OpenSSH and utilities such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chiark.greenend.org.uk/~sgtatham/putty/&#34;&gt;PuTTY&lt;/a&gt; that make it possible to use SSH for application specific VPNs as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Mac OS X, the following command in Terminal will create an application specific VPN to encrypt IMAP traffic to a remote server:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ssh -L 1143:imapserver.domain.com:143 -N -f user@sshserver.domain.com
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This same technique could be used to encrypt WebDAV traffic to a remote web server, other types of mail traffic (POP3 or SMTP, for example), RDP (for Remote Desktop), etc. Note that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work well with HTTP traffic that requires the use of host headers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few graphical utilities on Mac OS X for managing SSH tunnels; these include &lt;a href=&#34;http://projects.tynsoe.org/en/stm/&#34;&gt;SSH Tunnel Manager&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leapingbytes.com/almostvpn&#34;&gt;AlmostVPN&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not being a regular day-to-day Linux user (not on the desktop, at least), I don&amp;rsquo;t know of any SSH tunnel management applications, but I would be very surprised if they didn&amp;rsquo;t exist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Creating Site-to-Site Application Specific VPNs&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the examples so far have been using SSH and/or Stunnel to connect endpoints (i.e., a single laptop or desktop computer) to a remote resource via an application specific VPN. However, it&amp;rsquo;s also easily possible to create application specific site-to-site VPNs, whose purpose is to secure only a particular type of traffic between two locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this example. CompanyA wants to send e-mail to CompanyB, but wants that e-mail to be secure. If both mail servers support TLS, then the organizations could use TLS to secure the SMTP traffic. If not, then the companies can use Stunnel to establish an SSL connection between two systems. HostA at CompanyA can use Stunnel as a client side application to listen for unencrypted connections and pass them as encrypted connections to HostB at CompanyB. HostB at CompanyB is using Stunnel to listen for encrypted connections and passes them unencrypted to the mail server at CompanyB. With a simple configuration, the mail servers at both companies can be configured to pass mail connections for other company through the Stunnel connection. With no additional cost and very little configuration, all e-mail traffic between the two organizations has now been secured. All this without the complexity of a typical B-to-B VPN and the associated access controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, documents on &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/downloads/ptd-asvpn-ssh.doc&#34;&gt;application specific VPNs with SSH&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/downloads/ptd-asvpn-stunnel.doc&#34;&gt;application specific VPNs with Stunnel&lt;/a&gt; are available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Updating Kubuntu to KDE 3.5</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/01/updating-kubuntu-to-kde-35/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 21:52:39 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/01/updating-kubuntu-to-kde-35/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://kubuntu.org/&#34;&gt;Kubuntu&lt;/a&gt; 5.10, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kde.org/&#34;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt;-based variant of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntulinux.org/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, normally comes with KDE 3.4.3. With KDE 3.5.0 just recently released, however, I wanted to update Kubuntu to use the latest version of KDE. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I had to do to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, from &lt;a href=&#34;http://kubuntu.org/announcements/kde-35.php&#34;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt;, I downloaded and added the appropriate GPG key. Once that was done, I used &amp;ldquo;apt-get update&amp;rdquo; to download the latest package information and &amp;ldquo;apt-get upgrade&amp;rdquo; to upgrade packages. That upgraded most of KDE, but there were a few packages that still refused to upgrade (they were reported by apt-get as &amp;ldquo;held back&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After poking around with apt-get for a while, I discovered that there was one missing file&amp;mdash;libgnokii2&amp;mdash;that couldn&amp;rsquo;t be found in the apt-get sources. I manually reviewed the apt-get sources and finally found this package in the universe section of the main Ubuntu apt-get source. I edited /etc/apt/sources.list to enable the other sections, then manually installed the missing file with these commands:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get clean  
apt-get update  
apt-get install libgnokii2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then edited &lt;code&gt;/etc/apt/sources.list&lt;/code&gt; again to disable the other sources and upgraded the remainder of the KDE packages:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get clean  
apt-get update  
apt-get upgrade
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This last round of apt-get removed a few obsolete packages and then updated the remainder of the KDE packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is the &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; way of doing things, but it seemed to be the only way to make it work as anticipated. If anyone has a better way, please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Kubuntu 5.10</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/01/kubuntu-510/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2005 17:24:12 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/01/kubuntu-510/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;After wrestling with installing, configuring, and supporting Fedora Core 3 on an older Compaq Armada E500 laptop, I decided to break with my Red Hat/Fedora legacy and try &lt;a href=&#34;http://kubuntu.org/&#34;&gt;Kubuntu&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kde.org/&#34;&gt;KDE&lt;/a&gt;-based &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ubuntulinux.org/&#34;&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt; variation. Ubuntu itself is a relative newcomer to the Linux distribution arena, based on (as I understand it) &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.debian.org/&#34;&gt;Debian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous stints using Linux as my desktop OS, I&amp;rsquo;d always been partial to KDE instead of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gnome.org/&#34;&gt;GNOME&lt;/a&gt;. Some would say that it&amp;rsquo;s because KDE has traditionally been more &amp;ldquo;Windows-like&amp;rdquo; than the other Linux graphical environments; perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s the case. I&amp;rsquo;ve typically found KDE easier to work with, and since this laptop would eventually be used by the kids I felt like ease of use was important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The install went very quickly and very smoothly. When the install was done, I then proceeded to update KDE to version 3.5.0 (which had just been released a few days before). Along the way, I learned a handy piece of information about HTTP proxies and command-line utilities (I&amp;rsquo;ll soon post information on that as well). Eventually, I managed to get apt-get to download and install the updated KDE 3.5 packages. I rebooted the system and found that I was now running the updated version of KDE. (Side note: There are still some KDE packages that won&amp;rsquo;t upgrade for some reason; I&amp;rsquo;m currently working on resolving that issue.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still too early to tell for certain, but I may just have found a new desktop Linux version.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Microsoft&#39;s Counter-Move</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/21/microsofts-counter-move/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2005 23:16:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/21/microsofts-counter-move/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The rallying cry around OpenDocument prompted Microsoft to make its counter-move. As fully expected, Microsoft is trying to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1891829,00.asp&#34;&gt;create a standard&lt;/a&gt; based on Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s own (until now) proprietary XML formats. Please tell me you saw this coming, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With companies from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.novell.com/&#34;&gt;Novell&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.corel.com/&#34;&gt;Corel&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1895,1877815,00.asp&#34;&gt;standing in support&lt;/a&gt; of the OpenDocument format, a new coalition forming in support of the format, and governments agencies such as the State of Massachusetts requiring the use of file formats such as PDF and OpenDocument, clearly Microsoft was worried. Otherwise, why try to create an alternate standard of your own creation? Why not just join the existing standards? Many are also saying that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s decision to include PDF support in the next version of Office is another attempt to keep from being shut out. After all, Office is a major cash cow for Microsoft, so the company will do whatever it can to provent a loss of marketshare (and revenue as a result).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Can Somebody Help Me With MapFS?</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/09/can-somebody-help-me-with-mapfs/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2005 16:23:20 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/09/can-somebody-help-me-with-mapfs/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A pair of recent articles (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1880142,00.asp&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;em&gt;eWeek&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://trends.newsforge.com/article.pl?sid=05/11/03/2255215&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; at NewsForge) have me a bit perplexed. What&amp;rsquo;s the real value of MapFS? I know I have to be missing something here. Somebody send me an e-mail and explain it to me, or give me an example (other than the Live CD example mentioned in one of the articles above) of how this could be used effectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Open Source on Mac OS X</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/06/open-source-on-mac-os-x/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2005 12:04:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/06/open-source-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Most people automatically equate &amp;ldquo;open source&amp;rdquo; with Linux or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache&lt;/a&gt;. But there&amp;rsquo;s more to open source than that. There are a wide variety of open source projects that are also targeted at (gasp) &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Windows&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a Mac user myself, I was particularly interested in &lt;a href=&#34;http://software.newsforge.com/article.pl?sid=05/09/20/166254&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; recently posted at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newsforge.com/&#34;&gt;NewsForge&lt;/a&gt;. Some of the projects listed there were new to me; for example, I had never heard of or used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opencommunity.co.uk/vienna2.html&#34;&gt;Vienna&lt;/a&gt;. Given that I don&amp;rsquo;t like brushed metal interfaces (can&amp;rsquo;t stand them) and that I already use a commercial RSS reader, Vienna won&amp;rsquo;t do me much good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the projects listed there, though, I was familiar with and actually using currently. For example, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adiumx.com/&#34;&gt;Adium X&lt;/a&gt; is my default IM client (I use it to stay connected to MSN, AIM, and Google Talk), &lt;a href=&#34;http://cyberduck.ch/&#34;&gt;Cyberduck&lt;/a&gt; is my FTP/SFTP client, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://growl.info/&#34;&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; helps keep me informed about what is happening with all the various applications I have running. I&amp;rsquo;ve never used &lt;a href=&#34;http://seashore.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Seashore&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have a look at it soon (I&amp;rsquo;ve been looking for a good image editor).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nothickmanuals.info/doku.php?id=opensourcemac&#34;&gt;This link&lt;/a&gt; (also referenced in the NewsForge article) lists an even larger variety of open source Mac applications. Again, some I recognize (and use), a lot that I don&amp;rsquo;t. If you are a Mac user, I encourage you to take another look at some of the many high-quality open source projects available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Moving Back to Desktop Manager</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/04/moving-back-to-desktop-manager/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2005 09:00:32 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/04/moving-back-to-desktop-manager/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last few days or so, I have been experimenting with &lt;a href=&#34;http://virtuedesktops.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Virtue&lt;/a&gt;, a virtual desktop application. I&amp;rsquo;ve used various virtual desktop applications since switching to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/09/30/virtual-desktops-on-mac-os-x/&#34;&gt;this blog posting&lt;/a&gt;). After getting used to the lack of a desktop pager, I was really beginning to like Virtue and it&amp;rsquo;s functionality, even though it seemed as though the Virtue project had slowed and/or stopped development. Finally, after searching around for some way of re-instating the &amp;ldquo;Run Application&amp;rdquo; feature in &lt;a href=&#34;http://desktopmanager.berlios.de/&#34;&gt;Desktop Manager&lt;/a&gt;, I found that Virtue was incompatible with Mac OS X 10.4, aka &amp;ldquo;Tiger.&amp;rdquo; Since I&amp;rsquo;ve been researching the possibility of an upgrade to Tiger, I decided I&amp;rsquo;d better switch back to an application that was supposed to run under Tiger (which, based on what I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to find, Desktop Manager does).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a real shame, too. Virtue has a great feature set (I love the idea of the &amp;ldquo;primitives,&amp;rdquo; which are text and/or colors that can be applied to individual desktops). I didn&amp;rsquo;t use the per-desktop wallpaper functionality or the per-desktop icons, but I know a few people whose desktop-centric filing system would have really loved those features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I were a programmer, I&amp;rsquo;d probably pick up the code myself and run with it. But I&amp;rsquo;m not, so there you go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Virtual Desktops on Mac OS X</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/30/virtual-desktops-on-mac-os-x/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2005 22:15:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/30/virtual-desktops-on-mac-os-x/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Almost from the moment I switched to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;, I started looking for an application to provide the functionality of &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_desktop&#34;&gt;virtual desktops&lt;/a&gt;. I suppose my days of dabbling with Linux and the X Window System had ingrained me to believe that a *nix-based system just wasn&amp;rsquo;t the same without virtual desktops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My virtual desktop journey started with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codetek.com/ctvd/&#34;&gt;CodeTek Virtual Desktop&lt;/a&gt;, a commercial product that&amp;rsquo;s very capable. The idea of the desktop pager was very natural, and the ability to automatically switch desktops when switching applications was very handy. I could simply Alt-Tab to the application I needed and CodeTek would automatically switch the appropriate desktop. I could also specify that new windows for a particular application should always be created on a particular desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, I started looking into a new crop of open source virtual desktop managers. &lt;a href=&#34;http://space.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Space.app&lt;/a&gt; was one, but was (granted, this was quite some time ago) still a bit too rough around the edges. I was then turned on to &lt;a href=&#34;http://desktopmanager.berlios.de/&#34;&gt;Desktop Manager&lt;/a&gt;, which I used for long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desktop Manager wasn&amp;rsquo;t as full-featured in some aspects as CTVD, but I really liked the desktop transitions (great way to show off Mac OS X&amp;rsquo;s graphics functionality). The ability to support CTVD pager skins was a nice feature as well, and I really like the overlay of the desktop name on the desktop. One feature that I particularly enjoyed using was the Mac equivalent of the Run dialog box, invoked by Option-Cmd-R. This made it easy to launch an application without having to navigate to the desktop where the Applications folder was found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just within the last day or so, I started using &lt;a href=&#34;http://virtuedesktops.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Virtue&lt;/a&gt;. Virtue&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;claim to fame&amp;rdquo; is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t use a desktop pager to switch virtual desktops; instead, it uses a translucent pop-up window similar to that used by &lt;a href=&#34;http://quicksilver.blacktree.com/&#34;&gt;Quicksilver&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m having a bit of a problem getting used to the lack of a desktop pager, but the pop-up bezel is kind of cool, and it looks as if Virtue supports different wallpapers for different desktops. Virtue also appears to be more advanced with regards to applying desktop overlays (like the desktop name, for example). All in all, it looks like a great application. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ll stay with it or not; if I do switch back to Desktop Manager, it will be simply because I am too ingrained to use the desktop pager and because I miss my &amp;ldquo;Run&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; keyboard shortcut. In the meantime, I&amp;rsquo;m going to give it an honest try.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>YAMB (Yet Another Mac Browser)</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/05/yamb-yet-another-mac-browser/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2005 16:33:03 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/05/yamb-yet-another-mac-browser/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the title may indicate otherwise, I&amp;rsquo;m actually glad to see more browsers popping up for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;. Choice is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new kid on the block this time is &lt;a href=&#34;http://hmdt-web.net/shiira/index-e.html&#34;&gt;Shiira&lt;/a&gt;, a WebKit-based browser that offers some pretty useful features. These features include Tab Expose, which is Expose for browser tabs (activated via F8); &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growl.info/&#34;&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; integration; integration with Safari Bookmarks; and a clean, native Aqua interface. Because it uses Apple&amp;rsquo;s WebKit (now open sourced and available &lt;a href=&#34;http://webkit.opendarwin.org/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), it renders pages the same way as Safari.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like some features about Shiira (especially the Growl integration and the tabbed browsing implementation), but still find myself going back to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org/&#34;&gt;Camino&lt;/a&gt;. A new alpha version of Camino 0.9 has been released, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t brought myself to use it yet. If Camino had a way to provide notifications via Growl (I&amp;rsquo;d really like for my browser to notify me when a download is complete), I would be just absolutely thrilled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and Shiira is an open source project, released under a BSD style license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Open Source Office Alternative</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/03/open-source-office-alternative/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2005 22:57:03 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/03/open-source-office-alternative/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Those individuals searching for an open source alternative to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/office/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Office&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; isn&amp;rsquo;t the only Microsoft monopoly, you know) on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; should take note of NeoOffice/J 1.1, released a few weeks ago. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macnn.com/articles/05/06/21/neooffice.j.1.1.released/&#34;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macnn.com/&#34;&gt;MacNN&lt;/a&gt; alerted me to the release a while ago, but I&amp;rsquo;ve only just now gotten around to mentioning it here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve made no secret of the fact that I try not to be partial in any way with regards to technology solutions. If NeoOffice/J fits your needs, perfect. If not, use Microsoft Office. It&amp;rsquo;s just nice to see that we actually &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; some choices, however limited they may be, when it comes to choosing office productivity software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also hoping that the approval of the XML-based OpenOffice 2.0 file formats by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oasis-open.org/&#34;&gt;OASIS&lt;/a&gt; (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1819239,00.asp?&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;) will help further spur more interoperability between office productivity applications. Now, if we could just get Microsoft on board with this vendor-neutral format&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Transparent RDP Tunneling, Part 2</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/01/transparent-rdp-tunneling-part-2/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 22:54:45 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/01/transparent-rdp-tunneling-part-2/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;After some fiddling around with &lt;a href=&#34;http://stunnel.mirt.net/index.html&#34;&gt;Stunnel&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org/&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt;, I got the transparent RDP tunneling inside SSL working. I still need to run some network captures with Ethereal or similar to make sure that the traffic is encrypted, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see any reason why it won&amp;rsquo;t be. Overall, the process was a bit easier than I expected. Once I get it better documented, I&amp;rsquo;ll find an appropriate format in which to distribute the information for others to use in their own networks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Not the Same</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/25/not-the-same/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2005 22:58:42 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/25/not-the-same/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I just finished installing the latest version (3.7) of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org/&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt;, and I was reminded of just how different OpenBSD and Linux really are. Those on the &amp;ldquo;outside&amp;rdquo; just see them as Unix-like operating systems, but they really are much more different than you might expect. I&amp;rsquo;m no expert in either (I just dabble), but the differences are even evident to me. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet had the opportunity to experiment with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freebsd.org/&#34;&gt;FreeBSD&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netbsd.org/&#34;&gt;NetBSD&lt;/a&gt;, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know if these differences are particular to OpenBSD or to all BSDs when compared to Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, I find that I really like OpenBSD. I think that the more that I use OpenBSD, the more ways I will find that I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; use OpenBSD. It won&amp;rsquo;t replace Linux in my environment, but it is a very worthy addition to the network.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Preferred Mac OS X Applications</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/20/preferred-mac-os-x-applications/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 00:36:34 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/20/preferred-mac-os-x-applications/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I suppose I should go ahead and post the obligatory list of preferred &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; applications. So, without further ado, here goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SFTP Client:&lt;/em&gt; I used to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://rsug.itd.umich.edu/software/fugu/&#34;&gt;Fugu&lt;/a&gt;, but switched not too long ago to &lt;a href=&#34;http://cyberduck.ch/&#34;&gt;Cyberduck&lt;/a&gt;. I like Cyberduck&amp;rsquo;s Synchronize feature (to keep local and remote directories synchronized) and the built-in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growl.info/&#34;&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; support. I still keep Fugu around, but don&amp;rsquo;t use it nearly as much as I did.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Web Browser:&lt;/em&gt; I primarily use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.caminobrowser.org/&#34;&gt;Camino&lt;/a&gt;, although I will use Safari from time to time. I know that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; is available in a Mac OS X version, but I just prefer Camino.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Usenet Client:&lt;/em&gt; I tried a couple of open source applications, but finally settled on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.panic.com/unison/&#34;&gt;Unison&lt;/a&gt;. My only complaint with Unison is that I can&amp;rsquo;t post a message to a newsgroup and send a copy of the message to someone&amp;rsquo;s e-mail address at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;RSS Reader:&lt;/em&gt; Again, I tried a couple different applications (like &lt;a href=&#34;http://ranchero.com/netnewswire/&#34;&gt;NetNewsWire Lite&lt;/a&gt;) but was most satisfied with &lt;a href=&#34;http://freshsqueeze.com/products/pulpfiction/&#34;&gt;PulpFiction&lt;/a&gt;. The Mail.app-like interface and built-in Growl support fit my work habits well.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Instant Messaging:&lt;/em&gt; The open source &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.adiumx.com/index.php&#34;&gt;Adium&lt;/a&gt; client won my heart, although &lt;a href=&#34;http://fire.sourceforge.net/&#34;&gt;Fire&lt;/a&gt; was a very close second.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Organization:&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.omnigroup.com/applications/omnioutliner/&#34;&gt;OmniOutliner&lt;/a&gt; is a great application, very versatile and very flexible. I&amp;rsquo;ve found numerous uses for it so far, and expect that I&amp;rsquo;ll continue to find more and more ways to use this application.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Miscellaneous Applications:&lt;/em&gt; These applications defy any sort of categorization. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.growl.info/&#34;&gt;Growl&lt;/a&gt; notification system, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ecto.kung-foo.tv/&#34;&gt;ecto&lt;/a&gt; blogging client, &lt;a href=&#34;http://desktopmanager.berlios.de/&#34;&gt;Desktop Manager&lt;/a&gt; virtual desktop application, and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scifihifi.com/cocoalicious/&#34;&gt;Cocoalicious&lt;/a&gt; del.icio.us client all have a home on my PowerBook.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I can&amp;rsquo;t live without &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/mac/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Office&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/ical/&#34;&gt;iCal&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/isync/&#34;&gt;iSync&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.omnigroup.com/applications/omnigraffle/&#34;&gt;OmniGraffle&lt;/a&gt;, and others. This list should at least get things started.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>New del.icio.us Links</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/14/new-delicious-links/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2005 00:42:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/14/new-delicious-links/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve added a couple new links to &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/slowe/&#34;&gt;my del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt; bookmarks. Most notably, I&amp;rsquo;ve added an entry for a recent article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onlamp.com/&#34;&gt;ONLamp.com&lt;/a&gt;, a site hosted by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreillynet.com/&#34;&gt;O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Network&lt;/a&gt;, on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.modsecurity.org/&#34;&gt;mod_security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onlamp.com/pub/a/onlamp/2005/06/09/wss_security.html?page=1&#34;&gt;Securing Web Services with mod_security&lt;/a&gt;, is a great introduction to an &lt;a href=&#34;http://httpd.apache.org/&#34;&gt;Apache&lt;/a&gt; module that I&amp;rsquo;ve known about and used for a while now. Similar to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/technet/security/tools/urlscan.mspx&#34;&gt;URLScan&lt;/a&gt; for IIS 5.0, mod_security serves to block malicious URLs and invalid requests, even within encrypted HTTPS sessions. As such, it acts as the perfect complement to firewalls and intrusion detection/prevention systems (both network-based and host-based), which typically operate at lower layers of the networking stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use Apache, I urge you to evaluate and deploy mod_security to enhance your web server&amp;rsquo;s security.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Perdition Working Now</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/15/perdition-working-now/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2005 16:31:02 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/15/perdition-working-now/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally managed to get &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vergenet.net/linux/perdition/&#34;&gt;Perdition&lt;/a&gt; working. Still unable to confirm if &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Mail.app supports STARTTLS (my experience thus far says No), I had to resort to using &lt;a href=&#34;http://stunnel.mirt.net/index.html&#34;&gt;Stunnel&lt;/a&gt; to wrap IMAP inside an SSL tunnel, then forward the IMAP traffic to Perdition on the same host. The Perdition proxy then passes the traffic to the back-end mail server. It&amp;rsquo;s not the solution that I really wanted, but it will do for now. At least the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/&#34;&gt;Exchange Server 2003&lt;/a&gt; IMAP server isn&amp;rsquo;t exposed directly to external networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a slightly related note, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slipstick.com/&#34;&gt;Slipstick Systems&lt;/a&gt; web site has a link to an IMAP proxy server that implements STARTTLS as a workaround for Exchange&amp;rsquo;s lack of native support for STARTTLS. The IMAP proxy can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slipstick.com/files/imapproxysvc.zip&#34;&gt;http://www.slipstick.com/files/imapproxysvc.zip&lt;/a&gt;. So, if you have an IMAP4 client that supports STARTTLS and want to connect it to Exchange, you can use this IMAP proxy. At least, until &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; puts STARTTLS support into Exchange directly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Miscellaneous Projects</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/13/miscellaneous-projects/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 22:22:53 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/13/miscellaneous-projects/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In my copious spare time (fellow parents out there know this is a joke), I&amp;rsquo;m working on a couple of miscellaneous technical projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Internal news server:&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m having so many problems with NNTP-based access from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.panic.com/unison/&#34;&gt;Unison&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/&#34;&gt;Exchange Server 2003&lt;/a&gt; that I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to setup an internal NNTP server using Linux and INNd. Linux I&amp;rsquo;m familiar with; INNd is completely new to me. Wish me luck.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IMAP proxy:&lt;/em&gt; This would use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vergenet.net/linux/perdition/&#34;&gt;Perdition&lt;/a&gt; to proxy IMAP4S requests to my mail server. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably have Perdition handle IMAP4S and then pass IMAP to the back-end server, offloading the SSL work to the proxy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Squid log analysis:&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a way to parse down the logs from my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squid-cache.org/&#34;&gt;Squid&lt;/a&gt; web cache. Once I find a way to do this, then I can really begin offering Squid and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.squidguard.org/&#34;&gt;SquidGuard&lt;/a&gt; as a content filtering solution to some of my customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure this stuff is probably old hat to some of you out there. Feel free to contribute some helpful information or URLs. I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you posted on how things proceed with these and other projects as they develop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
