<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/categories/personal/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-12-24 19:26:11 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Merry Christmas!</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/24/merry-christmas/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2005 19:26:11 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/24/merry-christmas/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a moment to wish everyone a very Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year! I hope that the Lord blesses each of you very richly in the coming year. Let us be sure not to forget the true reason for this season&amp;mdash;the birth of Jesus Christ, our Lord and Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Happy Thanksgiving!</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/24/happy-thanksgiving/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2005 20:30:07 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/24/happy-thanksgiving/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you that celebrate the holiday, I&amp;rsquo;d like to wish you a very happy Thanksgiving. May the Lord richly bless you in the coming year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Another Take on Life(song)</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/22/another-take-on-lifesong/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2005 12:57:33 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/22/another-take-on-lifesong/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/&#34;&gt;earlier posting&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;em&gt;Lifesong&lt;/em&gt;, the second CD by the Christian group &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castingcrowns.org/home.php&#34;&gt;Casting Crowns&lt;/a&gt;, I spoke primarily about their musical style and their sound. At the time, I was so wrapped up in how the music sounded in comparison with their debut album that I was disappointed in this latest effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued listening to the CD, concentrating mostly on the tracks that I really enjoyed&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Lifesong&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Praise You in This Storm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Set Me Free&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Father, Spirit, Jesus&amp;rdquo;. As I listened&amp;mdash;truly listened&amp;mdash;to the words of these songs, and then took the time to listen to the other songs on the album as well, I realized that I was guilty of the very things that Casting Crowns sings about in these songs. And my first review was the perfect indicator of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many people practice Christianity on the surface. Sure, they go to church. They may even teach Sunday School, or lead a Bible study group. But do they really serve the Lord? Is their service&amp;mdash;my service&amp;mdash;just &amp;ldquo;empty hands held high&amp;rdquo;? How often do we high our true feelings from others, even our fellow Christians, becoming &amp;ldquo;happy plastic people under shiny plastic steeples&amp;rdquo;? Can we see past that young unwed mother&amp;rsquo;s sin, see &amp;ldquo;past her scarlet letter&amp;rdquo; and actually get to know her?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This entry isn&amp;rsquo;t just about a CD, though; that&amp;rsquo;s why I titled this post &amp;ldquo;Another Take on Life(song)&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about &lt;em&gt;Lifesong&lt;/em&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s about &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s time for us&amp;mdash;for me&amp;mdash;to move past superficial Christianity and into true service for the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean full-time ministry, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean just going to church. It means serving the Lord with all that we are and in all that we do (and my use of the term &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; here includes myself). It means living a life that &amp;ldquo;brings a smile&amp;rdquo; to the Lord, where we take to heart Jesus&amp;rsquo; teachings and actually apply them in all areas of life, not just the areas that are convenient or comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means letting our life(song) sing to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Lifesong by Casting Crowns</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2005 00:06:08 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I received a copy of the new album by Casting Crowns today, &lt;em&gt;Lifesong&lt;/em&gt;. There are a couple of really good tracks, like the title track &amp;ldquo;Lifesong,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Father, Spirit, Jesus&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Set Me Free.&amp;rdquo; Most of the songs, though, are a very different style than Casting Crowns&amp;rsquo; debut album. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit disappointed. After so thoroughly enjoying their first CD, I was really looking forward to their next album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that the CD is bad. It just wasn&amp;rsquo;t what I had expected. Songs from their first album really moved you, like &amp;ldquo;Voice of Truth&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Who Am I&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;American Dream&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;If We Are The Body&amp;rdquo;. And they did so with a powerful rock sound. These songs, on the other hand, are much softer. The lyrics are good, but the musical style is not what I was hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again, a few of the tracks from the original album didn&amp;rsquo;t really strike me the first time I heard them, but as I listened to them again I began to enjoy them more. Perhaps the same will happen here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Back From Sweden</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/09/back-from-sweden/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2005 22:35:06 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/09/back-from-sweden/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;We (my wife and I) got back from Sweden on Wednesday, after a thoroughly unpleasant flight experience. After 8 hours of flight in the middle seat, delays in the flight back from Stockholm caused us to miss our flight in Newark, NJ, introducing yet another delay in our return home. Finally, around 6:00 PM EDT, we arrived at the Raleigh-Durham airport, only 3 hours behind our original arrival time. Keep in mind, though, the 6 hour time difference between Raleigh and Sweden; to our bodies, it&amp;rsquo;s now 12:00 AM midnight &lt;em&gt;the next day&lt;/em&gt; and we&amp;rsquo;ve been traveling for a grand total of 18 hours (we left Stockholm around 6:00 AM in the morning). Let&amp;rsquo;s just say that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t the most pleasant flight experience we&amp;rsquo;ve ever had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aside from the flight home, the trip was enjoyable overall. It was good to see my old friend, who had invited us in the first place for his wedding. The weather was absolutely fantastic; you couldn&amp;rsquo;t ask for better weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two things that really stick with me from the trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we as Americans are spoiled, and should really learn to appreciate how God has blessed our country. Even with elevated gas prices resulting from Hurricane Katrina, we&amp;rsquo;re still not anywhere close to the $6-7/gallon that gasoline costs in Europe (adjusting, of course, for differences in currency and their use of the metric system).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, people are just people. I can&amp;rsquo;t tell you how many times we were walking in Stockholm or shopping in the grocery store and found it almost easy to forget that we were half a world away, in a foreign land, speaking a foreign language. Why? Because people there are no different than people here, with their own set of dreams, goals, fears, concerns, etc., just like anyone else. They just happen to speak a very different language and live in a very different land. Think about that next time you start believing that you are the only one that&amp;rsquo;s having a particular problem or issue, and remember that people all around the globe live their life day-by-day just like you do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll post more information about our trip to Sweden in future entries, perhaps including some of the photos of downtown Stockholm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Keeping Priorities in Check</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/17/keeping-priorities-in-check/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2005 18:23:01 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/17/keeping-priorities-in-check/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As technical people, we often immerse ourselves in our work to a far greater extent than people in other fields do. Why? I would imagine that most people, like myself, find this field to be as much of a hobby as it is a career. Sometimes, that&amp;rsquo;s fine, as it gives us the necessary technical edge to excel in a highly competitive arena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes we take it too far. As I was driving to work this morning, the song &amp;ldquo;American Dream&amp;rdquo; by Casting Crowns (great Christian rock group, by the way; see their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castingcrowns.org/&#34;&gt;web site&lt;/a&gt;) started playing. Listening to the song&amp;rsquo;s lyrics, I was reminded of the real priorities in life (all lyrics copyrighted by Casting Crowns):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Not this time son I&amp;rsquo;ve no time to waste&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Maybe tomorrow we&amp;rsquo;ll have time to play&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And then he slips into his new BMW&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;And drives farther and farther and farther away&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So he works all day and tries to sleep at night&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;He says things will get better;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Better in time&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How many times have we worked late to finish up that &amp;ldquo;important project&amp;rdquo;? You know, the one that just couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait until tomorrow? Too many times. Of course, this isn&amp;rsquo;t the first time this song has spoken to my heart; I&amp;rsquo;ve been a fan of Casting Crowns from practically Day One, and this song has always been a powerful one. I thank God that I realized my priorities were wrong years ago, and started putting God and my family first. I say that not to lift myself up or to speak highly of myself, but to give God the glory. To the rest of you techies out there, take note: It &lt;strong&gt;is&lt;/strong&gt; possible to be successful in this field without sacrificing what really matters in life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Matthew West&#39;s New Album</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/18/matthew-wests-new-album/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2005 00:03:21 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/18/matthew-wests-new-album/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I stopped by the local &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lifewaystores.com/lwstore/&#34;&gt;LifeWay&lt;/a&gt; yesterday to spend a gift card the kids had purchased for me as a Father&amp;rsquo;s Day gift. While I was there, I found that the latest album from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.matthewwest.com/&#34;&gt;Matthew West&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;History&lt;/em&gt;, was available, so I picked up a copy. Good stuff! I&amp;rsquo;d heard the latest single from the album, &amp;ldquo;Next Thing You Know,&amp;rdquo; on the radio, but as I was listening to it again this morning on the way to church God really blessed me again. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how a song that maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve heard a dozen times or more can really touch your heart. To me, that&amp;rsquo;s just another indicator that no matter how much we think we know God, there&amp;rsquo;s still more to Him than we could ever imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, go grab a copy of &lt;em&gt;History&lt;/em&gt; and listen to it. I think the Lord will really speak to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Going to Sweden</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/10/going-to-sweden/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2005 23:21:40 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/10/going-to-sweden/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, barring some unforeseen disaster or God leading us otherwise, my wife and I are going to Stockholm, Sweden, around Labor Day. A good friend of mine is getting married and we&amp;rsquo;ve been invited to the wedding. It&amp;rsquo;s a bit scary, as the only foreign country I have ever visited was Mexico, and that was to a high-traffic tourist area. Somehow, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that thousands of Americans visit Stockholm in September every year. Anybody know any Swedish?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Happy July 4th!</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/03/happy-july-4th/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2005 23:04:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/03/happy-july-4th/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For those readers in the US, I want to wish you a very enjoyable and very happy Fourth of July! As we celebrate another year of independence and freedom, take some time to remember those soldiers fighting overseas to preserve our freedom here as well as to give others the same kind of freedom. Also take the time to thank the one true Author of freedom, and that is God. May God bless each of you, and may God bless America!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>A Shameless Plug</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/20/a-shameless-plug/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 21:58:45 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/20/a-shameless-plug/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;OK, I know this is a shameless plug, but I just published an updated version of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mercurionsystems.com&#34;&gt;Mercurion Systems web site&lt;/a&gt; this evening. Have a look!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Finally Back From Vacation</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/finally-back-from-vacation/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 13:38:51 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/finally-back-from-vacation/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got back from my family vacation in Florida. It was (for the most part) a very relaxing two weeks. I had the opportunity to visit a small &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.churchofgod.cc/&#34;&gt;Church of God&lt;/a&gt; congregation in Kissimmee, FL (the Living Waters Church of God&amp;ndash;if you live in the area or are going to be visiting the area, go by and see them) and was alerted to a potential ministry for my wife and I within the church. We&amp;rsquo;ll see where God leads with that. Of course, I also had the chance to see some theme parks, swim in the pool, go to the beach, and spend some time with my family. All in all, a well-deserved and well-enjoyed vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>An Unexpected Answer</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/15/an-unexpected-answer/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2005 21:15:10 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/15/an-unexpected-answer/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever prayed a prayer, only to have God answer that prayer in the most unexpected, most unplanned way possible? Today, on Pentecost Sunday, the day in which we celebrate the giving of the Holy Spirit, God answered a prayer for me. In one of those really weird ways that only make sense when viewed through the eyes of faith, God blessed me with a burden. And through this burden I will have the opportunity to show His love, His grace, and His mercy. Praise the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Shaohannah&#39;s Hope</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/13/shaohannahs-hope/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 22:16:08 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/13/shaohannahs-hope/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe that we should support adoption as an alternative to abortion. In the absence of a serious medical need to abort a baby, there seems no reason to me to kill a baby when lots of couples would love to adopt that child and raise it as their own. That&amp;rsquo;s especially true when they can&amp;rsquo;t have children of their own naturally. Of course, when it comes to a subject like this everyone has their own opinion. That&amp;rsquo;s OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you believe like I do, then I would encourage you to look into supporting &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shaohannahshope.org/&#34;&gt;Shaohannah&amp;rsquo;s Hope&lt;/a&gt;. This organization, launched by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stevencurtischapman.com/&#34;&gt;Steven Curtis Chapman&lt;/a&gt; and his wife, Mary Beth Chapman, seeks to encourage adoption as a Christian ministry. It&amp;rsquo;s something worth praying about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Welcome</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/11/welcome/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2005 22:53:20 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/11/welcome/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to try a weblog of my own. As indicated in the title, I can&amp;rsquo;t promise regular updates, I can&amp;rsquo;t promise any consistency in the topics I&amp;rsquo;ll post about, and I can&amp;rsquo;t promise that I won&amp;rsquo;t say something that might offend you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re OK with all of these caveats, then please read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, some general background about me. I&amp;rsquo;m an IT professional running my own company, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mercurionsystems.com/&#34;&gt;Mercurion Systems&lt;/a&gt;, based in the Raleigh, NC area. We&amp;rsquo;re currently a pretty small company, but hoping to grow in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also a dad, trying hard with my wife to raise our family. I won&amp;rsquo;t go into detail on my family here, such as providing names or ages of kids, or anything like that, because (to be perfectly honest) none of you really need to know that kind of information. Suffice it to say that it is a large family and that I am blessed to have them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that leads me to my final (and perhaps most important) piece of information, and that is that I am a Christian. That I am going to openly discuss my beliefs and my religion here will probably offend some people, but my Christianity and my faith are interwoven into all that I am and all that I do. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to speak honestly here and &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; involve my faith.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any event, I hope that something you find here will a) help you solve a technical problem; b) encourage you as a parent; or c) lift you up in your faith. At the very least, it should help you occupy some time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
