<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/categories/general/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-12-04 22:58:28 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Some Weblog Updates</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/04/some-weblog-updates/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 22:58:28 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/04/some-weblog-updates/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s been a few updates to this weblog over the last few days. Nothing major, just a few minor changes here and there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I&amp;rsquo;ve moved to showing excerpts only on the index page. Of course, the archives pages (both category archives as well as monthly archives) were already showing excerpts only. Note that RSS feeds are still showing the full content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full entry page (the &amp;ldquo;single page,&amp;rdquo; in WordPress parlance) now shows the sidebar as well. It seems to me that this makes navigation through the weblog a bit easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve already mentioned the link to automatically post an entry&amp;rsquo;s URL to &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/&#34;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt;; this link only shows up when reading the full post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>I Want One!</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/19/i-want-one/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2005 15:54:06 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/19/i-want-one/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;The new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sun.com/&#34;&gt;Sun&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;Galaxy&amp;rdquo; x64 servers (the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sun.com/servers/entry/x4100/specifications.jsp&#34;&gt;Sun Fire X4100&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sun.com/servers/entry/x4200/specifications.jsp&#34;&gt;Sun Fire X4200&lt;/a&gt;) are wicked cool. Hot-swappable 2.5&amp;rdquo; Serial Attached SCSI (SAS) drives&amp;hellip;dual-core &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amd.com/us-en/Processors/ProductInformation/0,,30_118_8796,00.html&#34;&gt;AMD Opteron&lt;/a&gt; CPUs&amp;hellip;quad built-in Gigabit Ethernet ports&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s enough to make me want one. Even better, they run Windows, Linux, or Solaris (all fully supported by Sun, too). It&amp;rsquo;s almost like having your cake and eating it, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>An Interesting Viewpoint</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/06/an-interesting-viewpoint/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2005 12:27:44 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/06/an-interesting-viewpoint/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know that I necessarily agree with his viewpoint, but in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/wlg/7977?CMP=OTC-13IV03560550&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;A fake freedom&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, the question is raised: Do we really own our data?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are the pictures uploaded to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt; still yours? What about the bookmarks you&amp;rsquo;ve posted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://del.icio.us/&#34;&gt;del.icio.us&lt;/a&gt;? Or the weblog entries on a free weblog service such as &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogger.com/&#34;&gt;Blogger&lt;/a&gt;? You think so? Says who?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truly paranoid people could be worried that these services might maintain copies of their information, even after the user has requested that they be deleted. Of course, if you are really worried about copies of stuff, you may want to think about the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; cache&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very least, it would probably be a good idea to keep copies of this kind of information somewhere other than these &amp;ldquo;free&amp;rdquo; services. Otherwise, you just never know when a site may suddenly go dark, so to speak, for any number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Unrelated Items</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/22/unrelated-items/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2005 22:16:21 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/22/unrelated-items/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a few things I wanted to mention here, but none of them were really long enough to warrant their own entry. So, I&amp;rsquo;m lumping them all together here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, I&amp;rsquo;ve started going back and adding excerpts (or summaries) to most of the entries posted on this weblog. This makes the WordPress archive views cleaner (no more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/&#34;&gt;Technorati&lt;/a&gt; tags showing up for short entries). I&amp;rsquo;m sure there are probably other reasons why this is a good idea as well, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know what they are (yet).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, the process of adding these excerpts has reminded me of how challenging writing can be. I was always taught to have a firm purpose and focus when writing, and in those cases where that was true the summaries come to me easily. However, for those entries where my focus wandered, I am finding it difficult to summarize and describe what was written. This just really reinforces for me the challenge and the reward of writing here, of being able to effectively communicate and relate ideas to others. It&amp;rsquo;s a skill that many have lost (or never gained) in recent years, and society is worse for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve finally managed to get all of the weblog customizations in place, at least for now. It&amp;rsquo;s not a radical departure from the default WordPress theme, I know, but it&amp;rsquo;s a decent first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OK, so maybe these things are related after all&amp;hellip;they all have to do with this weblog.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Practicality Perspective</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/30/the-practicality-perspective/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2005 21:16:43 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/30/the-practicality-perspective/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent opinion article from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;eWeek&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; titled &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1826033,00.asp&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Hot Ideas Don&amp;rsquo;t Always Win the Race&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; (or &amp;ldquo;Just too hot an idea,&amp;rdquo; in the print version of &lt;em&gt;eWeek&lt;/em&gt;) takes a very practical view of Apple&amp;rsquo;s move to the Intel platform. Basically, while the PowerPC is technologically superior to x86 CPUs, the best technology doesn&amp;rsquo;t always win. We saw this with OS/2 (far superior to Windows 95) and the MCA bus architecture, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with him. As technical people, we need to be sure to take a step back from the &amp;ldquo;this technology is better&amp;rdquo; argument and look at the choice from a practicality perspective. And that goes not only for assessing this specific incident, but for the rest of our technical decisions as well. Sure, Linux may be superior to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windows/&#34;&gt;Windows&lt;/a&gt; from a technology perspective (I&amp;rsquo;m not saying it is or it isn&amp;rsquo;t), but is it the most practical decision? Sure, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org/&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; may be far superior to Linux (again, I&amp;rsquo;m not saying it is or it isn&amp;rsquo;t), but is it the most practical decision? Does it make the most sense not only from a technical viewpoint, but also from a business perspective? From a cost perspective?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be successful in our IT careers, we must look at these kinds of things from all perspectives, including the practicality perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>New Hyperlinking Convention</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/new-hyperlinking-convention/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 14:57:10 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/new-hyperlinking-convention/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m adopting a new hyperlinking convention with this post and all future posts. From this post on (I&amp;rsquo;ve actually been doing this already for the last few posts), I&amp;rsquo;ll only hyperlink the first instance of a company, product, term, etc., rather than all instances of that item within a posting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
