<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/tags/imap/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-07-02 20:47:16 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>STARTTLS and IMAP in Mail.app</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/02/starttls-and-imap-in-mailapp/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2005 20:47:16 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/02/starttls-and-imap-in-mailapp/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/05/14/nonstandard-implementations/&#34;&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; earlier about my frustration with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; Mail.app mail client and its apparent lack of STARTTLS support with IMAP4. Well, on a whim today I decided to take this issue back up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/&#34;&gt;Microsoft Exchange&lt;/a&gt; does not support STARTTLS, I had to use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vergenet.net/linux/perdition/&#34;&gt;Perdition&lt;/a&gt; as an IMAP proxy in front of Exchange. Earlier attempts to get Mail.app to do STARTTLS had failed (not sure why), but today I decided to try changing the IMAP port from 993 (the default when you check the &amp;ldquo;Use SSL&amp;rdquo; box) to 143 (the standard IMAP4 port). Oddly enough, it seemed to work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curious to find out for sure, I trotted out tcpdump on the mail gateway running Perdition to capture traffic to/from Mail.app and to/from the back end mail server. The traffic to/from the back end mail server was transmitted in the clear (I used plain text messages so that I could see the content), but the traffic to/from Mail.app was not readable. I also saw Mail.app issue a CAPABILITY command, then issue a STARTTLS command. Bingo!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it appears that Mail.app does indeed support STARTTLS for IMAP, but only if you set the port number back to 143 after checking the &amp;ldquo;Use SSL&amp;rdquo; checkbox.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Perdition Working Now</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/15/perdition-working-now/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2005 16:31:02 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/15/perdition-working-now/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally managed to get &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vergenet.net/linux/perdition/&#34;&gt;Perdition&lt;/a&gt; working. Still unable to confirm if &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; Mail.app supports STARTTLS (my experience thus far says No), I had to resort to using &lt;a href=&#34;http://stunnel.mirt.net/index.html&#34;&gt;Stunnel&lt;/a&gt; to wrap IMAP inside an SSL tunnel, then forward the IMAP traffic to Perdition on the same host. The Perdition proxy then passes the traffic to the back-end mail server. It&amp;rsquo;s not the solution that I really wanted, but it will do for now. At least the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/&#34;&gt;Exchange Server 2003&lt;/a&gt; IMAP server isn&amp;rsquo;t exposed directly to external networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a slightly related note, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slipstick.com/&#34;&gt;Slipstick Systems&lt;/a&gt; web site has a link to an IMAP proxy server that implements STARTTLS as a workaround for Exchange&amp;rsquo;s lack of native support for STARTTLS. The IMAP proxy can be found at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slipstick.com/files/imapproxysvc.zip&#34;&gt;http://www.slipstick.com/files/imapproxysvc.zip&lt;/a&gt;. So, if you have an IMAP4 client that supports STARTTLS and want to connect it to Exchange, you can use this IMAP proxy. At least, until &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; puts STARTTLS support into Exchange directly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Nonstandard Implementations</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/14/nonstandard-implementations/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2005 22:24:04 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/14/nonstandard-implementations/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In my experiments with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vergenet.net/linux/perdition/&#34;&gt;Perdition&lt;/a&gt;, I learned a couple of very interesting facts. First, the IMAP4 implementation on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/exchange/&#34;&gt;Exchange Server 2003&lt;/a&gt; does not support the STARTTLS command, as described in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.networksorcery.com/enp/rfc/rfc2595.txt&#34;&gt;RFC 2595&lt;/a&gt; and re-affirmed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.networksorcery.com/enp/rfc/rfc3501.txt&#34;&gt;RFC 3501&lt;/a&gt;. Instead, Exchange expects an SSL session to be established immediately, and then IMAP is spoken. This is similar to the &amp;ldquo;smtpd_tls_wrappermode&amp;rdquo; directive that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.postfix.org/&#34;&gt;Postfix&lt;/a&gt; supports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, it appears that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; Mail application (commonly referred to as Mail.app) also uses this IMAP-over-SSL approach, since I&amp;rsquo;ve been using Mail.app to connect to Exchange using IMAP with SSL for quite some time. I&amp;rsquo;m trying to confirm that now, but having precious little luck finding any definitive information one way or the other. If anyone knows for certain, please let me know. I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep searching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of those things that just makes me crazy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
