<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/tags/christianity/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-12-24 19:26:11 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Merry Christmas!</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/24/merry-christmas/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2005 19:26:11 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/24/merry-christmas/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to take a moment to wish everyone a very Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year! I hope that the Lord blesses each of you very richly in the coming year. Let us be sure not to forget the true reason for this season&amp;mdash;the birth of Jesus Christ, our Lord and Savior.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Happy Thanksgiving!</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/24/happy-thanksgiving/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2005 20:30:07 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/24/happy-thanksgiving/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you that celebrate the holiday, I&amp;rsquo;d like to wish you a very happy Thanksgiving. May the Lord richly bless you in the coming year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Another Take on Life(song)</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/22/another-take-on-lifesong/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2005 12:57:33 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/22/another-take-on-lifesong/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/&#34;&gt;earlier posting&lt;/a&gt; about &lt;em&gt;Lifesong&lt;/em&gt;, the second CD by the Christian group &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castingcrowns.org/home.php&#34;&gt;Casting Crowns&lt;/a&gt;, I spoke primarily about their musical style and their sound. At the time, I was so wrapped up in how the music sounded in comparison with their debut album that I was disappointed in this latest effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I continued listening to the CD, concentrating mostly on the tracks that I really enjoyed&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Lifesong&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Praise You in This Storm&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Set Me Free&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Father, Spirit, Jesus&amp;rdquo;. As I listened&amp;mdash;truly listened&amp;mdash;to the words of these songs, and then took the time to listen to the other songs on the album as well, I realized that I was guilty of the very things that Casting Crowns sings about in these songs. And my first review was the perfect indicator of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many people practice Christianity on the surface. Sure, they go to church. They may even teach Sunday School, or lead a Bible study group. But do they really serve the Lord? Is their service&amp;mdash;my service&amp;mdash;just &amp;ldquo;empty hands held high&amp;rdquo;? How often do we high our true feelings from others, even our fellow Christians, becoming &amp;ldquo;happy plastic people under shiny plastic steeples&amp;rdquo;? Can we see past that young unwed mother&amp;rsquo;s sin, see &amp;ldquo;past her scarlet letter&amp;rdquo; and actually get to know her?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This entry isn&amp;rsquo;t just about a CD, though; that&amp;rsquo;s why I titled this post &amp;ldquo;Another Take on Life(song)&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about &lt;em&gt;Lifesong&lt;/em&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s about &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;life&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s time for us&amp;mdash;for me&amp;mdash;to move past superficial Christianity and into true service for the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean full-time ministry, and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean just going to church. It means serving the Lord with all that we are and in all that we do (and my use of the term &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rdquo; here includes myself). It means living a life that &amp;ldquo;brings a smile&amp;rdquo; to the Lord, where we take to heart Jesus&amp;rsquo; teachings and actually apply them in all areas of life, not just the areas that are convenient or comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It means letting our life(song) sing to the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Lifesong by Casting Crowns</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2005 00:06:08 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/25/lifesong-by-casting-crowns/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I received a copy of the new album by Casting Crowns today, &lt;em&gt;Lifesong&lt;/em&gt;. There are a couple of really good tracks, like the title track &amp;ldquo;Lifesong,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Father, Spirit, Jesus&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Set Me Free.&amp;rdquo; Most of the songs, though, are a very different style than Casting Crowns&amp;rsquo; debut album. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m a bit disappointed. After so thoroughly enjoying their first CD, I was really looking forward to their next album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is not to say that the CD is bad. It just wasn&amp;rsquo;t what I had expected. Songs from their first album really moved you, like &amp;ldquo;Voice of Truth&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Who Am I&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;American Dream&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;If We Are The Body&amp;rdquo;. And they did so with a powerful rock sound. These songs, on the other hand, are much softer. The lyrics are good, but the musical style is not what I was hoping for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then again, a few of the tracks from the original album didn&amp;rsquo;t really strike me the first time I heard them, but as I listened to them again I began to enjoy them more. Perhaps the same will happen here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Matthew West&#39;s New Album</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/18/matthew-wests-new-album/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2005 00:03:21 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/18/matthew-wests-new-album/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I stopped by the local &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lifewaystores.com/lwstore/&#34;&gt;LifeWay&lt;/a&gt; yesterday to spend a gift card the kids had purchased for me as a Father&amp;rsquo;s Day gift. While I was there, I found that the latest album from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.matthewwest.com/&#34;&gt;Matthew West&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;History&lt;/em&gt;, was available, so I picked up a copy. Good stuff! I&amp;rsquo;d heard the latest single from the album, &amp;ldquo;Next Thing You Know,&amp;rdquo; on the radio, but as I was listening to it again this morning on the way to church God really blessed me again. It&amp;rsquo;s funny how a song that maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve heard a dozen times or more can really touch your heart. To me, that&amp;rsquo;s just another indicator that no matter how much we think we know God, there&amp;rsquo;s still more to Him than we could ever imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, go grab a copy of &lt;em&gt;History&lt;/em&gt; and listen to it. I think the Lord will really speak to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Happy July 4th!</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/03/happy-july-4th/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2005 23:04:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/03/happy-july-4th/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;For those readers in the US, I want to wish you a very enjoyable and very happy Fourth of July! As we celebrate another year of independence and freedom, take some time to remember those soldiers fighting overseas to preserve our freedom here as well as to give others the same kind of freedom. Also take the time to thank the one true Author of freedom, and that is God. May God bless each of you, and may God bless America!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Finally Back From Vacation</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/finally-back-from-vacation/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 13:38:51 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/finally-back-from-vacation/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I finally got back from my family vacation in Florida. It was (for the most part) a very relaxing two weeks. I had the opportunity to visit a small &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.churchofgod.cc/&#34;&gt;Church of God&lt;/a&gt; congregation in Kissimmee, FL (the Living Waters Church of God&amp;ndash;if you live in the area or are going to be visiting the area, go by and see them) and was alerted to a potential ministry for my wife and I within the church. We&amp;rsquo;ll see where God leads with that. Of course, I also had the chance to see some theme parks, swim in the pool, go to the beach, and spend some time with my family. All in all, a well-deserved and well-enjoyed vacation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>An Unexpected Answer</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/15/an-unexpected-answer/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 15 May 2005 21:15:10 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/15/an-unexpected-answer/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever prayed a prayer, only to have God answer that prayer in the most unexpected, most unplanned way possible? Today, on Pentecost Sunday, the day in which we celebrate the giving of the Holy Spirit, God answered a prayer for me. In one of those really weird ways that only make sense when viewed through the eyes of faith, God blessed me with a burden. And through this burden I will have the opportunity to show His love, His grace, and His mercy. Praise the Lord.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Shaohannah&#39;s Hope</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/13/shaohannahs-hope/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2005 22:16:08 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/05/13/shaohannahs-hope/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe that we should support adoption as an alternative to abortion. In the absence of a serious medical need to abort a baby, there seems no reason to me to kill a baby when lots of couples would love to adopt that child and raise it as their own. That&amp;rsquo;s especially true when they can&amp;rsquo;t have children of their own naturally. Of course, when it comes to a subject like this everyone has their own opinion. That&amp;rsquo;s OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you believe like I do, then I would encourage you to look into supporting &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shaohannahshope.org/&#34;&gt;Shaohannah&amp;rsquo;s Hope&lt;/a&gt;. This organization, launched by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stevencurtischapman.com/&#34;&gt;Steven Curtis Chapman&lt;/a&gt; and his wife, Mary Beth Chapman, seeks to encourage adoption as a Christian ministry. It&amp;rsquo;s something worth praying about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
