<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/tags/apple/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-06-13 13:41:02 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Apple on Intel</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/apple-on-intel/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2005 13:41:02 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/06/13/apple-on-intel/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;While I was away in Florida on vacation, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/&#34;&gt;Apple&lt;/a&gt; announced at WWDC 2005 that they will transition to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.intel.com/&#34;&gt;Intel&lt;/a&gt; CPUs over the next couple of years. I won&amp;rsquo;t try to predict what this will mean, or whether Apple will go away, or anything deep like that. It makes perfect sense from a hardware perspective; Apple needs faster CPUs because the whole theme of &amp;ldquo;processor speed doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter&amp;rdquo; just isn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it with the masses. The ordinary John and Jane Doe out there don&amp;rsquo;t know that a 2.5GHz G5 is as equally powerful as a 3.6GHz Pentium 4. They just know that the Pentium 4 is faster, and that means the system is better, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/powerbook/&#34;&gt;PowerBook&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt;, not for the PowerPC CPU inside. Did the PowerPC G4 processor add an era of mystique, of uniqueness? Sure. In the end, however, I bought a PowerBook because I liked Mac OS X and because I could get the applications I needed to get my work done on a Mac. If I can do that with an Intel-powered Mac that is just as fast or faster, then so be it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Truth be told, I do worry about Apple&amp;rsquo;s hardware business, though, and what this will mean for them. Time will tell.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
