<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Scott&#39;s Weblog </title>
    <link>http://lowescott.github.io/categories/microsoft/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Scott Lowe</author>
    <rights>(C) 2005</rights>
    <updated>2005-12-29 21:47:21 &#43;0000 &#43;0000</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>WMF Flaw Exploit Grows Worse</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/29/wmf-flaw-exploit-grows-worse/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 21:47:21 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/29/wmf-flaw-exploit-grows-worse/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;In an update to my previous article on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/12/28/windows-metafile-flaw-already-being-exploited/&#34;&gt;Windows Metafile flaw&lt;/a&gt;, new reports are coming in of greater use of malicious WMF files that take advantage of the flaw, especially by adware companies. Numerous sites are reporting that malicious WMF files are being used in ad rotations on third-party sites. For more information, see one of the following articles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analysts Fret as Adware Makers Leverage WMF Flaw
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1906915,00.asp&#34;&gt;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1906915,00.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critical Impact: Windows Metafile Flaw a &amp;lsquo;Zero-Day Exploit&amp;rsquo;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1906177,00.asp&#34;&gt;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1906177,00.asp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition, there are details on just how easy it is to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oreillynet.com/pub/wlg/8879?CMP=OTC-6YE827253101&amp;amp;ATT=Exploiting+the+Windows+XP/2003+Picture+and+Fax+Viewer+Metafile+Overflow+Vulnerability&#34;&gt;take advantage of this vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; available as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The particularly bad part of this whole situation is that users don&amp;rsquo;t have to do a thing&amp;mdash;just visiting a web site with a malicious WMF file can affect your system. And this isn&amp;rsquo;t an Internet Explorer flaw, either, lest you think that using Firefox will keep you safe. No, this is a &lt;em&gt;Windows&lt;/em&gt; flaw, and Internet Explorer, Firefox, Opera, etc., are all affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s hope that a good workaround (not unregistering the shimgvw.dll file, which also disables previewing other image formats in Windows Explorer) emerges soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Windows Metafile Flaw Already Being Exploited</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/28/windows-metafile-flaw-already-being-exploited/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2005 16:33:13 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/28/windows-metafile-flaw-already-being-exploited/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Two separate reports (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1906177,00.asp&#34;&gt;this article from eWeek&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computerworld.com/securitytopics/security/story/0,10801,107375,00.html&#34;&gt;this article from ComputerWorld&lt;/a&gt;) have risen today regarding a &amp;ldquo;zero-day&amp;rdquo; exploit of a vulnerability in Windows&amp;rsquo; handling of WMF (Windows Metafile) images. According to the reports, simply viewing a WMF file (such as from a web site) can infect your computer. Sunbelt Software&amp;rsquo;s blog also offers &lt;a href=&#34;http://sunbeltblog.blogspot.com/2005/12/new-exploit-blows-by-fully-patched.html&#34;&gt;more details on the vulnerability&lt;/a&gt; as well. Here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securityfocus.com/bid/16074/info&#34;&gt;more information&lt;/a&gt; from SecurityFocus as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the reports, this newly discovered WMF vulnerability will allow crackers to run the code of their choice on the affected system(s). So far, the exploit has been limited to installing spyware, adware, and keyloggers, but there is little doubt in anyone&amp;rsquo;s mind that the attackers will grow much worse very quickly. The vulnerability can be exploited in a variety of ways, such as visiting hostile web sites (using either Internet Explorer, Opera, or Firefox); opening an affected WMF file in Windows Picture and Fax Viewer; or previewing an affected file in Windows Explorer. It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that this vulnerability affects even fully patched systems &lt;em&gt;with all available patches installed.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently, the only workaround is to uninstall Windows from your computer and immediately install Linux. OK, just kidding. Seriously, though, the only known workaround at this time is to unregister the affected DLL using this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;regsvr32 /u shimgvw.dll
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &amp;ldquo;OK&amp;rdquo; when prompted. This unregisters the affected DLL and eliminates the vulnerability; however, this may also affect the viewing and previewing of many other types of images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still early yet in the discovery process, so I fully anticipate that more workarounds and more information will emerge as the security researchers continue their work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Complete Linux-AD Authentication Details</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/22/complete-linux-ad-authentication-details/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2005 11:26:46 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/22/complete-linux-ad-authentication-details/</guid>
          <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE:&lt;/strong&gt; These instructions are for Windows 2000 Server and Windows Server 2003 pre-R2. For the R2 release, please see &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2007/01/15/linux-ad-integration-version-4/&#34;&gt;these updated instructions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several articles posted here that discuss, in general terms, how to authenticate Linux against Active Directory. For example, see this brief article on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/07/13/linux-ad-integration-direction/&#34;&gt;broad direction&lt;/a&gt; of the integration, or this posting on &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/07/18/minor-linux-ad-hiccup-fixed-hopefully/&#34;&gt;using computer accounts&lt;/a&gt; for Linux servers (most how-to documents I&amp;rsquo;ve seen discuss the use of a user account for this purpose).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last week or so, I&amp;rsquo;ve been having to rebuild one Linux server a number of times in an effort to fix a separate problem (see this article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/08/16/strange-ntpd-problem-on-centos-41/&#34;&gt;NTPd problems with CentOS 4.1&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/12/19/ntpd-on-centos-42/&#34;&gt;recurrence of the problem&lt;/a&gt; with CentOS 4.2). As a result, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to go through the process of configuring this Linux server (and preparing Active Directory) for authentication several times, and I found that I kept having to go back to my scattered and dispersed notes to remember what had to be done. In the hopes of correcting that, I am collecting all the pertinent information I have here in this article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Preparing Active Directory (One-Time)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a one-time preparation of Active Directory that is required. In order to authenticate Linux logins against Active Directory, Active Directory&amp;rsquo;s schema must be extended to include Linux-specific attributes such as home directory, UID, GID, and default shell. There are a couple of different ways to do this; I chose to use Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Services for Unix (SFU) to extend the schema. There are two reasons I chose SFU: 1) it&amp;rsquo;s free; and 2) the SFU schema is being included by default in Windows Server 2003 R2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once SFU has been installed and the schema has been extended, then the specific Active Directory accounts that are allowed to authenticate via Linux must be configured with a UID and other UNIX attributes. This is accomplished via the new &amp;ldquo;UNIX Attributes&amp;rdquo; tab on the properties dialog box of a user account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to create an account in Active Directory that will be used to bind to Active Directory for LDAP queries. This account does &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; need any special privileges; in fact, making the account a member of Domain Guests and &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; a member of Domain Users is perfectly fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all the user accounts have been configured, then we are ready to perform the additional tasks within Active Directory and on the Linux server that will enable the authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Preparing Active Directory (Each Server)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each server that will be authenticating against Active Directory, follow the steps below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Create a computer account in Active Directory. When creating the computer account, be sure to specify that this account may be used by a pre-Windows 2000-based computer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Use the following command at a command prompt to configure the new computer account:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ktpass -princ host/fqdn@REALM -mapuser DOMAIN\name$&lt;br /&gt;
-crypto DES-CBC-MD5 -pass password -ptype KRB5_NT_PRINCIPAL&lt;br /&gt;
-out filename&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to substitute the appropriate values for &amp;ldquo;fqdn&amp;rdquo; (the fully-qualified domain name of the computer), &amp;ldquo;REALM&amp;rdquo; (the DNS name of your Active Directory domain in UPPERCASE), &amp;ldquo;DOMAIN&amp;rdquo; (the NetBIOS name of your Active Directory domain), &amp;ldquo;password&amp;rdquo; (the password that will be set for the new computer account), and &amp;ldquo;filename&amp;rdquo; (the keytab that will be generated and must be copied over to the Linux computer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need to rebuild the Linux server for whatever reason, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to delete the computer account you created and repeat this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Preparing the Linux Server&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow the steps below to configure the Linux server for authentication against Active Directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Make sure that the appropriate Kerberos libraries, OpenLDAP, pam_krb5, and nss_ldap are installed. If they are not installed, install them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Be sure that time is being properly synchronized between Active Directory and the Linux server in question. Kerberos requires time synchronization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the &lt;code&gt;krb5.conf&lt;/code&gt; file to look something like this, substituting your actual host names and domain names where appropriate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[logging]&lt;br /&gt;
 default = FILE:/var/log/krb5libs.log&lt;br /&gt;
 kdc = FILE:/var/log/krb5kdc.log&lt;br /&gt;
 admin_server = FILE:/var/log/kadmind.log&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[libdefaults]&lt;br /&gt;
 default_realm = EXAMPLE.COM&lt;br /&gt;
 dns_lookup_realm = true&lt;br /&gt;
 dns_lookup_kdc = true&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[realms]&lt;br /&gt;
 EXAMPLE.COM = {&lt;br /&gt;
  kdc = host.example.com:88&lt;br /&gt;
  admin_server = host.example.com:749&lt;br /&gt;
  default_domain = example.com&lt;br /&gt;
 }&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[domain_realm]&lt;br /&gt;
 .example.com = EXAMPLE.COM&lt;br /&gt;
 example.com = EXAMPLE.COM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[kdc]&lt;br /&gt;
 profile = /var/kerberos/krb5kdc/kdc.conf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[appdefaults]&lt;br /&gt;
 pam = {&lt;br /&gt;
   debug = false&lt;br /&gt;
   ticket_lifetime = 36000&lt;br /&gt;
   renew_lifetime = 36000&lt;br /&gt;
   forwardable = true&lt;br /&gt;
   krb4_convert = false&lt;br /&gt;
 }&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the &lt;code&gt;/etc/ldap.conf&lt;/code&gt; file to look something like this, substituting the appropriate host names, domain names, account names, and distinguished names (DNs) where appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;host 10.10.10.10
base dc=example,dc=com
binddn cn=ldap,cn=Users,dc=example,dc=com
bindpw adldapbindpw
scope sub
ssl no
nss_base_passwd dc=example,dc=com
nss_base_shadow dc=example,dc=com
nss_base_group dc=example,dc=com
nss_map_objectclass posixAccount user
nss_map_objectclass shadowAccount user
nss_map_objectclass posixGroup group
nss_map_attribute uid sAMAccountName
nss_map_attribute uidNumber msSFU30UidNumber
nss_map_attribute gidNumber msSFU30GidNumber
nss_map_attribute loginShell msSFU30LoginShell
nss_map_attribute gecos name
nss_map_attribute userPassword msSFU30Password
nss_map_attribute homeDirectory msSFU30HomeDirectory
nss_map_attribute uniqueMember msSFU30PosixMember
nss_map_attribute cn cn&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Securely copy the file created using the &lt;code&gt;ktpass.exe&lt;/code&gt; utility above to the Linux server in question, placing it in the &lt;code&gt;/etc&lt;/code&gt; directory as &lt;code&gt;krb5.keytab&lt;/code&gt;. (SFTP or SCP are excellent candidates for this.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Configure PAM (this varies according to Linux distributions) to use pam_krb5 for authentication. Many modern distributions use a stacking mechanism whereby one file can be modified and those changes will applied to all the various PAM-aware services. For example, in Red Hat-based distributions, the system-auth file is referenced by most other PAM-aware services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the &lt;code&gt;/etc/nsswitch.conf&lt;/code&gt; file to include &amp;ldquo;ldap&amp;rdquo; as a lookup source for passwd, shadow, and groups.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That should be it. Once you do that, you should be able to use &lt;code&gt;kinit&lt;/code&gt; from a Linux shell prompt (for example, &lt;code&gt;kinit aduser&lt;/code&gt;) and generate a valid Kerberos ticket for the specified Active Directory account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, any PAM-aware service that is configured to use the stacked system file (such as the system-auth configuration on Red Hat-based distributions) will use Active Directory for authentication. Note, however, that unless you also add the &lt;code&gt;pam_mkhomedir.so&lt;/code&gt; module in the PAM configuration, home directories will have to be created manually for any Active Directory account that may log on to that server. (I generally recommend the use of &lt;code&gt;pam_mkhomedir.so&lt;/code&gt; in this situation.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Mass Password Changes in Active Directory</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/08/mass-password-changes-in-active-directory/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2005 22:16:58 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/12/08/mass-password-changes-in-active-directory/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year, I had a need in a project to set the password for a large number of Active Directory accounts simultaneously. Here&amp;rsquo;s the solution I came up with for this particular need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use this technique, you&amp;rsquo;ll need &lt;code&gt;ldifde&lt;/code&gt; (included with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/windowsserver2003/default.mspx&#34;&gt;Windows Server 2003&lt;/a&gt;), &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; (included with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/macosx/&#34;&gt;Mac OS X&lt;/a&gt; and most Linux distributions; Win32 versions available on the Internet), a text editor with search and replace functionality (advanced geeks are free to use &lt;code&gt;sed&lt;/code&gt;), and &lt;code&gt;dsmod&lt;/code&gt; (from the &lt;em&gt;Windows Server 2003 Resource Kit&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, export the list of user accounts out of Active Directory using ldifde. The command will look something like this (I&amp;rsquo;ve line wrapped here, as indicated by a backslash, but this should all be on one line):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ldifde -d &amp;quot;CN=Users,DC=company,DC=com&amp;quot; -r &amp;quot;(objectclass=user)&amp;quot; \  
-f c:\export-1.ldif
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This creates a file called &amp;ldquo;export-1.ldif&amp;rdquo;. Using &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt;, filter this file down to only the full distinguished names of the users:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;less export-1.ldif | grep &#39;dn: &#39; &amp;gt; export-2.ldif
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that you&amp;rsquo;ll need to use &lt;code&gt;type&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;less&lt;/code&gt; on a Win32 system. Also, on a Win32 system you&amp;rsquo;ll need to use double quotes instead of single quotes in the &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; command. This creates a file called &amp;ldquo;export-2.ldif&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Load this file into the text editor and make the following changes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remove all occurrences of &amp;ldquo;dn: &amp;ldquo; (there is a space after the colon)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a double quotation mark before CN= at the start of each line&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add a double quotation mark after =com at the end of each line&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save this modified file as &amp;ldquo;export-3.ldif&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, pipe this file through to the &lt;code&gt;dsmod&lt;/code&gt; program to set passwords for all the users in the file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;type export-3.ldif | dsmod user -pwd newpass1 -mustchpwd yes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full help for the dsmod command line syntax is available using &lt;code&gt;dsmod /?&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;dsmod user /?&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can add &lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; filename&lt;/code&gt; to the end of the above command to log the output of the &lt;code&gt;dsmod&lt;/code&gt; command to a file. You can then use &lt;code&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; to parse this file to ensure that the command was successful for all users.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Open Enough for Massachusetts</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/open-enough-for-massachusetts/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 16:45:01 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/open-enough-for-massachusetts/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Not suprisingly, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s moves to &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; up its XML-based file formats for current and future versions of Microsoft Office have swayed the State of Massachusetts back to its side again. Get the details &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windowsitpro.com/windowspaulthurrott/Article/ArticleID/48590/windowspaulthurrott_48590.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Microsoft Promises Not to Sue</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/microsoft-promises-not-to-sue/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2005 16:24:54 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/11/29/microsoft-promises-not-to-sue/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; recently made a move to &amp;ldquo;open&amp;rdquo; up its XML-based file formats for Microsoft Office 2003 and the forthcoming Office 12. These file formats were offered to ECMA International for consideration as a formal open standard. However, the &amp;ldquo;license&amp;rdquo; for these file formats was merely a promise not to sue people violating its patents on the use of the file formats. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1894039,00.asp&#34;&gt;Read more here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1895,1892757,00.asp&#34;&gt;these comments&lt;/a&gt; from a legal analyst regarding Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/office/xml/covenant.mspx&#34;&gt;Patent Protection Covenant&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, a promise &amp;ldquo;not to sue&amp;rdquo; from any large corporation&amp;ndash;not just Microsoft&amp;ndash;wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be good enough for me were I a developer. Somehow, I don&amp;rsquo;t think that many developers are going to feel completely comfortable incorporating Office &lt;sup&gt;2003&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;12&lt;/sub&gt; XML-based file formats into their applications based solely on the Patent Protection Covenant. What happens when (not if) the covenant changes?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Just in Case</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/08/just-in-case/</link>
          <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2005 17:58:09 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/10/08/just-in-case/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned the bug discussed in &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=kb;en-us;905809&#34;&gt;KB905809&lt;/a&gt; several times in this blog. In reading those posts (or reading the KB article), you&amp;rsquo;ve probably seen that you can use the SC.EXE command to set the security descriptors on the Service Control Manager to fix the bug. What happens, though, if you mess up the SC.EXE command?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that this very thing happened recently. A systems administrator copied the required SC.EXE command line from a Word document, thinking it was safer to copy and paste than try to type the command line directly. As it turns out, the copied text from Word had a carriage return in it, and this caused the command line to terminate early (before all the security descriptors were applied). In fact, what happened is that all of the &amp;ldquo;Write&amp;rdquo; permissions were removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run &amp;ldquo;sc sdshow scmanager&amp;rdquo; on a system running Windows Server 2003 SP1, you&amp;rsquo;ll get this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;D:(A;;CC;;;AU)(A;;CCLCRPRC;;;IU)(A;;CCLCRPRC;;;SU)  
(A;;CCLCRPWPRC;;;SY)(A;;KA;;;BA)S:(AU;FA;KA;;;WD)  
(AU;OIIOFA;GA;;;WD)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Side note: The first section is the problem area, as this is what grants permission to the Authenticated Users group. In the fix described in KB905809, this section changes to grant Authenticated Users more permissions.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this particular situation, all of the &amp;ldquo;Write&amp;rdquo; permissions&amp;mdash;everything after the &lt;code&gt;(A;;CCLCRPRC;;;SU)&lt;/code&gt; section&amp;mdash;was accidentally removed. So, when the administrator realized what had happened and went back to try to fix it the system kicked back an &amp;ldquo;Access Denied&amp;rdquo; error message, because the permissions had been removed. With no permission to change the permissions, what could be done?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, we found a fix. This &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exchangeserveradmin.org/ftopic24842_Could_NOT_change_mail_address_after_windows_server_2003_sp1.html&#34;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt; describes a Registry key that someone else had concocted trying to fix this very problem. In my discussions with Microsoft Product Support services, they analyzed this Registry hack and determined that the end result was the same as the SC.EXE command. By importing this Registry fix, we were able to restore the permissions that had been inadvertently removed. We then used SC again (with &amp;ldquo;sdshow scmanager&amp;rdquo;) to verify that the permissions were as they needed to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are fortunate that this Registry fix solved the problem. Had the Registry fix not worked, we most likely would have had to rebuild the server in question&amp;mdash;not a pleasant thought given that we had several hundred users already migrated over to that server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What can we learn from this situation? Here are my thoughts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Always type your commands by hand, instead of copying and pasting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Take appropriate precautions. In large-scale production environments, pull a hot-plug hard drive from the RAID array first. If things go south, shut the server down and reboot from the pristine drive.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;When running a command like this, pray.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real question, in my mind, is this: why isn&amp;rsquo;t Microsoft going to fix this bug? We may never know the answer to that question.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Error ID c10308a2 is Put to Rest</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/26/error-id-c10308a2-is-put-to-rest/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2005 13:45:18 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/26/error-id-c10308a2-is-put-to-rest/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As you may already know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been struggling with a bug in an environment running Exchange Server 2003 and Windows Server 2003 with SP1. The bug is manifested as an error that appears when users with the properly delegated permissions attempt to add or modify an e-mail address on an already mail-enabled or mailbox-enabled object. The error, listed as error ID c10308a2, contains text along the lines of being unable to determine if the Microsoft Exchange System Attendant service is running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underlying issue is a change that Windows Server 2003 SP1 makes to the security descriptors applied to the Service Control Manager. This change in security descriptors now makes it impossible for non-administrators to query service status; hence, the error message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In trying to apply the fix suggested by Microsoft in KB905809 (the use of the SC.EXE command), the error was never resolved. It turns out that the workstation I was using the test environment was configured not to use the primary DNS suffix, but instead use a predetermined DNS suffix search list. This configuration resulted in the system&amp;rsquo;s AD domain name &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; being in the suffix search list. As a result, even though the fix from Microsoft was applied, errors still occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I double-checked everything on the test servers as well as the test workstations, corrected the problem described above, and reset the environment to match the production environment. Then, walking through the tests again, I confirmed that running the SC command to add permissions to the Authenticated Users group (see the KB article linked above for more details, then see &lt;a href=&#34;http://msdn.microsoft.com/library/default.asp?url=/library/en-us/secauthz/security/security_descriptor_string_format.asp&#34;&gt;this explanation&lt;/a&gt; of SDDL syntax) &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; indeed resolve the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, finally, we can put this issue to rest. If you are running Exchange Server 2003 with Windows Server 2003 SP1 and finding that your non-administrative users can&amp;rsquo;t add or modify e-mail addresses using Active Directory Users &amp;amp; Computers, see KB905809 and run the SC command listed in there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Have You Seen Error ID c10308a2?</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/22/have-you-seen-error-id-c10308a2/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2005 17:52:13 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/22/have-you-seen-error-id-c10308a2/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As the next-to-last article in a series of postings about the problem described in this &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=kb;en-us;905809&#34;&gt;KB article&lt;/a&gt;, it appears that Microsoft will not be producing a hotfix for this bug. In speaking with Microsoft earlier today, it appears that no hotfix will be produced for this, even though it is a confirmed bug. As of this afternoon, the only known fix for the problem is using &lt;strong&gt;both&lt;/strong&gt; methods outlined in the KB article. I hope to confirm that for sure on Monday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also going to confirm on Monday whether membership in the local Administrators group (on the actual Exchange servers) will also fix the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next posting about this problem will be the last one regarding this issue. Really.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Inability to Add or Modify E-Mail Addresses</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/20/inability-to-add-or-modify-e-mail-addresses/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 17:01:38 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/20/inability-to-add-or-modify-e-mail-addresses/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a follow-up to my posting titled &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/09/14/another-funky-ad-issue/&#34;&gt;Another Funky AD Issue&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, in which I described a situation with a customer where support staff are unable to modify or add an e-mail address to a mail-enabled or mailbox-enabled user or contact after it has been created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that this is a bug in Windows Server 2003 SP1. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=kb;en-us;905809&#34;&gt;KB article&lt;/a&gt; I referenced in the earlier blog posting is also slightly inaccurate; what that article portrays as two separate workarounds to the problem are actually two steps in one workaround. So, in reality, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to perform &lt;strong&gt;both&lt;/strong&gt; steps (both the SC.EXE command and the Group Policy Object) in order to fix the problem. (Please note that I have not verified this myself yet.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it currently stands, the KB article is the only known workaround for this problem. According to the Microsoft Product Support Services people I&amp;rsquo;ve spoken with thus far, it is unknown if Microsoft will issue a hotfix to correct the problem. In the meantime, I have forwarded a URL with another potential fix (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.exchangeserveradmin.org/ftopic24842_Could_NOT_change_mail_address_after_windows_server_2003_sp1.html&#34;&gt;this URL&lt;/a&gt;) for Microsoft to analyze and determine if this will help the situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other potential solutions include adding the support staff to the local Administrators group on the Exchange server(s); this, clearly, is a less-than-ideal solution. Supposedly, removing Windows Server 2003 SP1 will also correct the problem. (Again, I have not verified this personally.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Product Support Services is supposed to get back in touch with me in the next couple of days with some additional information. I&amp;rsquo;ll post more information here as it becomes available.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Another Funky AD Issue</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/14/another-funky-ad-issue/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2005 23:08:57 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/09/14/another-funky-ad-issue/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This one is still unresolved. The basic gist of the arrangement is this: user accounts that have been delegated the appropriate permissions in Exchange System Manager and Active Directory in order to be able to manage user objects (including e-mail attributes) are unable to add or edit e-mail addresses on mail-enabled and mailbox-enabled objects. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; has a &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=kb;en-us;905809&#34;&gt;KB article&lt;/a&gt; that describes the issue perfectly, but the fix doesn&amp;rsquo;t work (at least, not for this specific implementation). The KB article and numerous hits from a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; search indicate that the use of SC.EXE from Windows Server 2003 SP1 can fix the problem, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, and the other workaround offered by the KB article isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly appealing (using Group Policy Objects in Active Directory to add permissions to a service across the network).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Funky Active Directory Issue</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/16/funky-active-directory-issue/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2005 23:17:43 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/08/16/funky-active-directory-issue/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I came across a funky Active Directory issue today. User objects stored in an OU on which permissions had been assigned were &amp;ldquo;losing&amp;rdquo; their permissions and their inheritance from the parent OU. For example, if the group &amp;ldquo;Support Team&amp;rdquo; had been granted a set of permissions on the OU &amp;ldquo;Sales&amp;rdquo;, then the user object &amp;ldquo;Bob Jones&amp;rdquo; stored in that OU would lose those permissions regularly. Even when the permissions were reassigned, they would disappear again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that if the user object is a member, directly or indirectly, of a &amp;ldquo;protected group&amp;rdquo; (such as Server Operators, Backup Operators, or Administrators), then Active Directory automatically removes any inherited permissions, resets those permissions to the default, and turns off inheritance for those objects. The idea is to prevent possible elevation of privileges. This behavior is described in &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.microsoft.com/default.aspx?scid=kb;en-us;817433&#34;&gt;this KB article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fix? Well, you can muck around in Active Directory and play with the adminSDHolder object, or you can just not worry about delegations on those user objects, or you can remove those user objects from the protected group in question. In my particular case, the user objects needed to be taken out of the protected group anyway, so that was a natural fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep this in mind when planning AD delegations and the placement of accounts that will be members of a protected group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linux-AD Integration Wrap-Up</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/22/linux-ad-integration-wrap-up/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2005 00:19:08 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/22/linux-ad-integration-wrap-up/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, my Linux-AD integration task is pretty much complete. I have three Linux servers authenticating via &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/kerberos/www&#34;&gt;Kerberos&lt;/a&gt; to Active Directory, and using LDAP for name/group resolution. Only one Linux server remains; I need to do some research on how &lt;a href=&#34;http://asg.web.cmu.edu/sasl/&#34;&gt;SASL&lt;/a&gt; with interact with PAM before I can switch over that particular server. My &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.openbsd.org&#34;&gt;OpenBSD&lt;/a&gt; server I&amp;rsquo;m going to leave alone for now; perhaps later I&amp;rsquo;ll get it integrated as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to see what is involved in using RADIUS to authenticate VPN tunnels on my hardware firewall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Rootkit Prevention Coming to Windows</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/19/rootkit-prevention-coming-to-windows/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2005 15:17:43 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/19/rootkit-prevention-coming-to-windows/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.scottlowe.org/2005/06/21/dangerous-stuff/&#34;&gt;blogged&lt;/a&gt; a while back about concerns that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spyware&#34;&gt;spyware&lt;/a&gt; makers were adding &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Root_kit&#34;&gt;rootkit&lt;/a&gt; functionality to their products to make them harder to detect and harder to remove. It seems that trend has gotten the attention of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;. (About time, I say.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/security/malwareremove/default.mspx&#34;&gt;Malicious Software Removal Tool&lt;/a&gt; has been enhanced with the ability to find and remove rootkit-like trojans and backdoor applications. In addition, Microsoft has indicated that it will likely &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1838294,00.asp&#34;&gt;incorporate anti-rootkit functionality&lt;/a&gt; into future versions of its &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/athome/security/spyware/software/default.mspx&#34;&gt;AntiSpyware&lt;/a&gt; product, acquired with Giant Software and still in beta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rootkits have been reported on virtually all major operating systems, so we can&amp;rsquo;t really knock Microsoft for allowing rootkits to infect Windows. We can, however, insist that as long as Microsoft makes it possible for the operating system to be compromised in such a significant way through the use of a web browser, then such stuff as &lt;a href=&#34;http://research.microsoft.com/rootkit/&#34;&gt;Strider Ghostbuster&lt;/a&gt; (Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s anti-rootkit technology) should continue to be offered to Windows users at no charge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Minor Linux-AD Hiccup Fixed (Hopefully)</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/18/minor-linux-ad-hiccup-fixed-hopefully/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2005 00:18:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/18/minor-linux-ad-hiccup-fixed-hopefully/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I think I have resolved one minor Linux-AD integration hiccup. In setting up the Kerberos authentication, various instructions I had found (including some from Microsoft) indicated I needed to create a &lt;em&gt;user&lt;/em&gt; account for the Linux servers, then use &lt;code&gt;ktpass&lt;/code&gt; to generate the Kerberos keytab. This works, but being the stickler for detail that I am, I really wanted to use a computer account instead of a user account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After fiddling with it for a while, I finally managed to make it work. The &lt;code&gt;ktpass&lt;/code&gt; command should look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;ktpass -princ host/fqdn@REALM -mapuser DOMAIN\name$  
-crypto DES-CBC-MD5 -pass password -ptype KRB5_NT_PRINCIPAL  
-out filename
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The missing piece, for me, was specifying &lt;code&gt;DOMAIN\name$&lt;/code&gt; for the mapuser parameter. Without it, the command kept generating an error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know for sure that this will work, but I will be testing this within the next day or so to see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Linux-AD Integration Success!</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/17/linux-ad-integration-success/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2005 22:31:52 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/17/linux-ad-integration-success/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, limited success, anyway. I have managed to get Linux authentication to occur via &lt;a href=&#34;http://web.mit.edu/kerberos/www&#34;&gt;Kerberos&lt;/a&gt; against Active Directory. LDAP is used to lookup the user and group information. Using pam_krb5, authentication occurs via Kerberos to an Active Directory DC for any PAM-aware application. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that I&amp;rsquo;ll find some hiccups along the way, but so far things look good. I only have 1 server configured this way for now (a non-essential server), but after some additional testing I&amp;rsquo;ll expand this to the remainder of my Linux servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll post more details here and/or on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mercurionsystems.com/index.html&#34;&gt;Mercurion Systems&lt;/a&gt; web site once all the bugs have been worked out. My thanks go out to the many, many individuals who posted information on using Kerberos and LDAP with Active Directory; this would not have been possible without their assistance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Ongoing Microsoft-Claria Saga</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/11/the-ongoing-microsoft-claria-saga/</link>
          <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2005 23:12:08 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/11/the-ongoing-microsoft-claria-saga/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Apparently, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/athome/security/spyware/software/claria_letter.mspx&#34;&gt;public statement&lt;/a&gt; regarding the downgrade of Claria software in their anti-spyware product (which now recommends that users ignore the Claria software instead of remove it) isn&amp;rsquo;t sitting well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1835770,00.asp&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; at &lt;em&gt;eWeek&lt;/em&gt;, a number of spyware experts call Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s explanation less than satisfactory. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.edbott.com/weblog/archives/000844.html&#34;&gt;Ed Bott&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.benedelman.org/news/063005-1.html&#34;&gt;Ben Edelman&lt;/a&gt;, and others have all commented on Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s explanation. The overwhelming consensus is that users don&amp;rsquo;t trust Microsoft to be honest. And why should they? Unfortunately, Microsoft has placed itself in an unenviable position, and only by being completely squeaky clean and transparent will it be able to avoid a backlash over actions such as this.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Enough Bundling Already!</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/07/enough-bundling-already/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2005 18:09:10 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/07/enough-bundling-already/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s bad enough that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt; bundles Internet Explorer and Windows Media Player with every copy of Windows, and then integrates them so deeply that a flaw in one of these applications can compromise the entire system. But bundling adware/spyware?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, there was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1833611,00.asp&#34;&gt;this rumor&lt;/a&gt; about Microsoft acquiring Claria, the company that distributes the Gator ad-serving software. It was just a rumor, and one that not very many people took seriously. But now, there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1834607,00.asp&#34;&gt;this news&lt;/a&gt; that Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s anti-spyware program has lowered the rating on Claria&amp;rsquo;s software and changed the default action to &amp;ldquo;Ignore.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean? In reality, nothing. It may have been just an oversight, or it may be that Claria has reached some sort of monetary agreement with Microsoft. In the meantime, I would recommend (as I have in the past) using multiple anti-spyware applications to protect yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Watch Out, IE Users</title>
          <link>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/01/watch-out-ie-users/</link>
          <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2005 17:32:09 &#43;0000</pubDate>
          <author>Scott Lowe</author>
          <guid>http://lowescott.github.io/2005/07/01/watch-out-ie-users/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of articles are highlighting a recently uncovered security flaw in Microsoft Internet Explorer&amp;ndash;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1833697,00.asp&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;eWeek&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.computerworld.com/securitytopics/security/story/0,10801,102924,00.html&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;em&gt;ComputerWorld&lt;/em&gt;, both of which reference this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/technet/security/advisory/903144.mspx&#34;&gt;security advisory&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.microsoft.com/&#34;&gt;Microsoft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fix is to set the Security Level for the Internet Zone to High, which disables the functionality required for the exploit to work. Unfortunately, it also disables a lot of other things that non-malicious sites use, so this workaround will affect your ordinary browsing experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recommendation is to switch to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/products/firefox/&#34;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt;. While Firefox was shown to be vulnerable to a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eweek.com/article2/0,1759,1830025,00.asp&#34;&gt;recent spoofing flaw&lt;/a&gt; (this flaw also affected IE, Safari, Camino, etc.), it&amp;rsquo;s still better than IE&amp;rsquo;s security record. And, yes, for those of you out there who are yelling at your computer screens right now: I know that you probably believe that Firefox is only more secure because there are fewer people using it. Perhaps that&amp;rsquo;s true, but the end result is that it&amp;rsquo;s more secure. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that what we are seeking to achieve?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
